<topics>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1888-11-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    British Bits.

                    The steamer Newburgh, of Leith, while on her voyage from Grangermouth to Aarhus, with coal, foundered in the North Sea. Sixteen persons were drowned and one was rescued and landed in Norway.

                    A private person living near Nottingham, has received a letter signed "Jack Ripper's pal," stating that both the writer of the letter and "Jack" committed the recent murders in White Chapel district. The writer says "Jack" is a Bavarian, whom he first met aboard a ship returning from Amarios, and who exercised a mesmeristic influence.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014381/1888-12-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "JACK, THE RIPPER."

                    A Montreal Crank, Who is Probably a Ripping Liar.

                    A man has been arrested here for assaulting a woman, who says he is "Jack, the Ripper." This evening, Miss Florier Newcome was was walking on Lagaucheterie estreet, ins dark quarter of the city, a man suddenly darted out of a gateway and caught her by the arm, exclaiming: "You must come with me!" The girl screamed, and break- ing away, rushed along the treet, closely followed by the man.

                    This man, when arrested, said: "I'm Jack, the Ripper! All Whitechapel is looking for me! I have just arrived. I inte intended to give myself up, as I have alreadly killed fifteen, and I'll yet com- plete the number if you let me go. You'd better hang me by the neck till I'm dead?"

                    He had name was John Langhorn, aged 25, of Lon- don. He is detained for further examination.

                </text>

            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1888-12-22/ed-1/?sp=1/&q=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    IS IT "JACK THE RIPPER" AGAIN?

                    ANOTHER FALLEN WOMAN FOUND MURDERED IN A SUBURB OF LONDON.

                    The body of a woman, whose name is unknown, was found yesterday morning in the streets of Poplar, in the suburbs of London. An empty vial lay alongside the body, and the impression first formed was that the woman had committed suicide. At the coroner's inquest today, however, the physicians who examined the body testified that there were no signs of poison in the stomach, and declared their belief that the woman had been murdered by strangulation. They said the condition of the body justified this belief, and in addition to that, there was a mark on the woman's neck which showed that a small cord had been tied tightly around it. The woman was of low character. When the body was found, it was still warm. It was lying in an open thoroughfare, and there is no possibility that the woman could have taken her own life. Some persons believe that her murderer is identical with the Whitechapel fiend, who, they think, has adopted a new method of disposing of his victims.
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1888-12-28/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Jack, the Ripper, Throws the People of Brussels Into a Spasm of Fear.

                    This city has been thrown into a ferment of excitement by the reception by prominent people of cards and telegrams announcing the advent in the quaint old city of the famous "Jack, the Ripper," of Whitechapel notoriety. King Leopold, the prefect of police, and the court ministers are among the recipients of this mysterious being's delicate attentions.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1889-01-05/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The Mania for Murder.

                    The English public are excited by the occurrence of murders in different parts of the kingdom which bear so strong a likeness to those committed by JACK the Ripper that they seem to be imitations of his horrible work. As in the Whitechapel murders, the bodies of the victims are mutilated. The killing seems to be done from a sheer mania for butchery, none of the usual motives being discoverable.

                    It is not at all impossible that JACK the Ripper has started a new school of murder and murderers. Human experience shows that the more morbid the criminal manifestations the more likely they are to stimulate imitation in other diseased natures. Mania breeds mania, or rather provokes it, in minds disposed to insanity, as one hysterical woman will set a whole hospital ward of women to screaming. The notoriety of the Whitechapel murders brought them to the attention of that large number of persons whose moral and intellectual balance is most likely to be upset, and among the simple they have been the most engrossing subject of thought and conversation.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1889-01-05/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The Mania for Murder.

                    The conditions favorable to the spread of a mania for imitation have therefore been present, and the circumstance that JACK the Ripper has not been caught and punish- ed for his horrible crimes has undoubtedly assisted in propagating a craze for killing for its own sake. Even the insane are de- terred from murder by dread of punishment, and fancied immunity from the penalties visited on the criminal becomes to them an Incentive to crime.

                    The fallure of the London police to bring the Whitechapel murderer to justice, so ex- traordinary in the history of crime, is there- fore a terrible social misfortune. It is mak- ing of him a hero and an example. Morbid minds are likely to be upset entirely by dwelling on his atrocities and his ability to commit them many times over without de- tection. Because he is inhuman, a flend in the form of a man, he excites devilish pro- pensities uncontrollable in others, except by the fear of certain punishment.

                    It is said by our police that even here in New York there has been much terror among the women of the street lest JACK the Ripper should appear in person or stimulate others to engage in his horrible specialty. The alarm of these women is not surprising. But, in New York, the career of such a murderer would be short. Because of that certainty, so generally understood, we are not likely to have imitations of the Whitechapel mur- ders, though, unless JACK the Ripper is brought to justice, they are likely to occur in England until he ceases to be a subject of public discussion and curiosity.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1890-10-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Balfour Starts on a Tour of Investigation Through the Western Counties of Ireland.

                    The "Jack-the-Ripper" scare is on again to-night. In a secluded part of the South Hampstead locality was found the dead body of a woman whose head had been nearly severed, while the body showed kicks and bruises sufficient to cause death. The victim was a woman of low repute, and this was sufficient to start the cry of "Jack the Ripper."
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1891-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    IT'S JACK THE RIPPER

                    The Notorious London Butcher Does a Regulation Job in New York City.

                    A Dissolute Woman of the Slums Murdered in Jack's Inimitable Style.

                    His Bloody Cross Is on the Base of the Spine of the Victim.

                    The Police Have a Good Description of the Murderer to Work On.

                    Now let the police of New York prove their boasted superiority over the police of London. Jack the Ripper is here. He has done his unspeakable work. His victim, mangled as he mangled her predecessors in the grim list in London, lies now as he left her in the garret where the deed was done. Further than that, the weapon used has been found and is in the hands of the police. But, more than all, Jack the Ripper himself was seen before he did his bloody work. The girl who saw him is able to give close and clear description of him, and if brought face to face with him can identify him positively. The story of the crime is horrible in its simplicity and in its familiarity. Under different surroundings, and with modifications incident to those surroundings, it is an exact repetition of the horrible atrocities of Whitechapel. The scene is in a little dirty squalid room up on the fourth and topmost floor of a wretched lodging house, known as the East River house, and kept by one James Jennings.

                    The nearest house is at the corner of Water and Catharine streets and is designated as 16 Catharine Slip. The entrance proper is on Water street. The door here opens into a short hallway. At the end of this passage, a flight of narrow, worn wooden stairs goes up to the floor above. Here a book is kept called a register, and in this register, Edward Fitzgerald, the clerk of the house, writes such names as persons seeking rooms for the night choose to give him. Through this Water street doorway and up the flight of stairs there came, at 10:45 last night, two persons. One was a woman who could not have been much under sixty years of age.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    JACK THE RIPPER'S MARK.

                    THE LONDON CRIMES IMITATED IN A WATER STREET STY.

                    After Butchering an Old Hag of the Streets the Murderer Berates & Cross Upon Her Body- He was Gone Hours Before the Body was Found- His Facets Known, Though, and the New York Police Have That Advantage Over Scotland Yard- He Left His Knife, Toss, and Carried Away the Key of the Room- A Bad Man Known as "Frenchy" Among Those Under Arrest- A Drag Net Cast In the Low Resorts- Inspector Byrnes Takes the Field In Person-Handling In Prisoners for Cross-examination.

                    The painted hags who swarm on the river front between Roosevelt and Catharine streets have lost one of their number. An imitator of Jack the Ripper, if not Jack himself, butchered her on Thursday night and escaped at his leisure, leaving her mutilated remains in the wretched room they had taken for the night. Last night a large force of police were dragging the low resorts of the neighborhood, and Inspectors Byrnes and Williams were at the station house cross-questioning the prisoners. They had found out who the murdered woman was.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94056415/1891-05-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Jack the Ripper in America.

                    "Jack the Ripper," is believed by the police to have at last come to this city. Yes- terday morning in the East River ho- tel the body of a wretched woman was found with her abdomen horribly cut and her bowels protruding. Her name is not known. The resort in which the body was found is one of the low- est in the city. It is located on the southeast corner of Catherine and Mar- ket streets. The woman was known about the neighborhood as one of the half drunken creatures who the low resorts of Waterbang about Riverside. She came to the hotel last night in company with a man who reg- istered as Knickioi and wife. The couple were assigned to a room on the upper floor and went to it at once. Nothing was seen or heard of them during the night. No cry or unusual noise was heard. This morning the attendant banged at the door of the room occupied by the couple.

                    There was no answer and he banged again with no better result and finally broke in the door. A horrible sight met his gaze. On the bed lay the woman in a big pool of blood. She had been dead for hours. Her abdomen had been fairly ripped open with a dull, broken table knife that lay in the pool of blood.

                    The viscera had been cut, and from appearances a part was missing. The woman's head was bandaged. A cloth had been tied about her neck and face, but whether for any foul purpose or to hide any other traces of murder the attendant did not wait to see.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063034/1894-12-02/ed-1/?sp=5&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    JACK THE RIPPER'S FATE.

                    The Famous Assassin Said to be Imprisoned in an Insane Asylum.

                    The mystery of "Jack the Ripper" is still one of the darkest of the unsolved chapters in the annals of human crime. So dramatically horrible were his murders and so fascinatingly baffling was the identity of this secret that the whole world was startled and astounded from the moment of the discovery of his first work of butchery. Mankind recognized a new species of crime, a new type of criminal, such as had hitherto never been revealed. A great sociological problem was provoked and "Jack the Ripper" became world-famous. He disclosed, so to speak, a distinct genius for crime, and has left upon the bloody pages of modern vice a name to stand beside that of the poisonous Borgia. He chose, indeed, a fit theater for his hideous iniquity, emerging like a grisly and ghastly specter of sin from the wretched shambles and purlieus of Whitechapel.

                    The stories of his murders read like the creeping fantasies of Poe. The scenes of his crimes resembled the horrors of the Rue Morgue. The same chilling mystery made the blood curdle. The tragedy of the forlorn, miserable women, the outcasts of hope who were his victims, moved all hearts to pity, while the murderer's bold audacity added a touch of sinister romance. There was the forewarning letter, written in a disguised hand to Dr. Forbes Winslow, the famous English physician, which simply read: "You will hear of me in a few days. Jack the Ripper." And then on the wall over the first dead body that was soon after found had written the bombastic line: "I will give myself up when I have killed fifteen. Jack the Ripper." The undoubted intelligence of the crafty executioner of the fallen women of London heightened, indeed, the intense public interest in the strange case.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025308/1892-08-18/ed-1/?sp=8&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    On the first heat of the five-sighths handicap the betting started in favor of Mike Brown, but interest switched to Red Dick, with Jack the Ripper in third place. Then Brown began to sell off again, and the close saw him bringing $120 to $40 for Jack the Ripper and Red Dick $36. The favorite got the worst of the start, the horse not moving up promptly. Bob Smith had the mount on the favorite and said he did not think it a "go." Red Dick got the lead at the start, with Jack the Ripper a good second. The horses came down toward the stretch in the same order, Red Dick and Jack the Ripper working for dear life to keep Mike Brown from catching up. The latter was coming along easily without punishment and apparently not saving back for the finish or the next heat. He had the pole and none of the others had closed in on him, though he was in the rear. Even then, as they turned into the home-stretch, it looked like Mike Brown would go to the front, but he fell out of it in the last furlong and let the others do the finish. They did it in great shape, and having the field practically to themselves, made a horse race out of it. Nearing the wire, Jack the Ripper went to the front a little. Then Red Dick drew up, and the two went under the wire with Jack the Ripper, by a fine burst of speed, about a neck ahead. Mike Brown was a very poor third.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1960-02-19/ed-1/?sp=35&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    If you like your movie whodunits gruesome and gory, Joe Levene, a movie importer trading as Embassy Pictures, has been reading your mind. He has answered your unspoken demand with a fogbound little British opus called "Jack the Ripper," which currently is spreading its blood-letting across the Metropolitan and Ambassador Theater screens.

                    The principal perpetrators of this obviously low budget melodrama seem to be a couple of fellows named Robert S. Baker and Monty Herman. They, at any rate, are credited with production, direction, and photography, which takes in considerable territory. To their credit, let it be said that some of their old-London-by-night photography is effective in capturing a mood of impending doom. Their editing, on occasion, is sharp in catching melodramatic tension.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1895-09-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Dr. Forbes Winslow of London well-known specialist on suicide and insanity, says that Jack the Ripper, who, by his crimes, terrorized London a few years ago, is incarcerated in a county lunatic asylum in England.

                    Mr. Winslow says this fact is known to the doctors, but they hushed up the facts.

                    The story told by Dr. Winslow is as follows: Jack the Ripper was a medical student of good family. He was a young man of slight build, with light hair and blue eyes. He studied very hard and his mind being naturally weak, gave way. He became a religious enthusiast and attended early service every morning at St. Paul's. His religious fever resulted in homicidal mania toward the women of the street, and impelled him to murder them. He lodged with a man whom I knew, and suspicion was first directed toward him by reason of the fact that he returned to his lodgings at unseasonable hours, and that he had innumerable coats and hats stained with blood.

                    I have in my possession now a pair of Canadian moccasins stained with blood which the Ripper wore while on his murderous expeditions. I notified the Scotland Yard authorities, but at that time they refused to co-operate with me. Subsequently, the young man was placed in confinement, and remanded to an asylum, where he is today. Since his incarceration, there has been no repetition of the horrible murders that he perpetrated. These facts are all known to the English authorities. And it is conceded the man now in the asylum is Jack the Ripper.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024271/1944-04-06/ed-1/?sp=4&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "The Lodger" is the story of the Jack The Ripper murders and features Merle Oberon, George Sanders and Laird Cregar, with the supporting cast including Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sara Allgood and Aubrey Mather.

                    Jack The Ripper, in a series of murders that had the whole world in terror, not only was never caught, but Scotland Yard never even came close to catching him and they do not even know whether Jack The Ripper was a Crime's most terrifying story and the masterpiece of murder mysteries.
                    
                </text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
</topics>