<topics>
  <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-gold-rush</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-gold-rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Grout Mountains of Mineral Wealth
                    Awaiting Development - The Need of Government Aid in Making Explorations.

                    Since the acquisition of Alaska in 1867 public attention in regard to it has been mainly directed to the salmon fisheries in its waters and to the seal rookeries in Behring sea. The value of the country as a dependency has been wholly determined by the public from the rental which the Priboloff islands yield to the national treasury. Few references in the intervening period have been made by public journals and in the periodical literature of the country to the gold-yielding capabilities of Alaska, or to the degree of development already reached. The truth is that hundreds of thousands of intelligent Americans are profoundly ignorant of the fact that some of the largest and most profitable gold mining enterprises within the limits of the United States are conducted in Alaska.

                    Gold in variable quantities and under different conditions has been found in three principal districts of Alaska: the Juneau and Douglass Island district, 180 miles northeast of Sitka and bordering Gasteneaux channel, a narrow inlet which separates Douglass island from the mainland; the Sitka district, the quartz deposits of which are found at Silver Bay, a narrow, tortuous arm of the Pacific, indenting Baranoff island, and in the valley of the Yukon river in western Alaska. Gold-bearing quartz has also been found at Unga island, one of the smaller of the Aleutian group, and some effort has been made there at development, but more of that hereafter.

                    As concerns the Yukon valley, little attention has been paid by explorers and prospectors to quartz, and the gold-bearing discoveries so far relate only to placer mining. At the head of Lynn canal, one of the inner passages adapted to steamer navigation, about 300 miles northeast of Sitka, is the mouth of the Chilcat river, navigable for canoes for a score of miles. At the head of this canoe navigation are three large Chilcat villages, and it is at this point where commences what is known as the Chilcat Portage, across the range to the headwaters of the Yukon river in British territory. The distance from the Indian villages on the American side of the divide to the first lake, the source of the Yukon, is about thirty miles. During the past three years, reports have emerged that the bars of the Yukon and its tributaries, Stewart and Polly rivers, and Forty-Mile creek were rich in placer gold, inducing several Alaska miners to venture across the range at the Chilcat crossing.

                    The permanent development of gold mining in Alaska has been concentrated in the southeastern part of the territory. This region, which embraces a thirty-mile wide strip of mainland, extending from Portland channel at the southern boundary to the vicinity of Mt. St. Elias, and including the islands of the Alexandrian Archipelago, is marked by very steep and lofty mountains, whose summits are rarely free from snow. Despite the challenging topography, gold mining has flourished here.

                    Gold quartz was first discovered in 1877 near Silver Bay, in the vicinity of Sitka, by Mr. Haley, a soldier discharged from the regular army, who had mining experience in Colorado and California. This discovery marked the beginning of a series of mining developments in the region. Although many early efforts failed due to insufficient capital and poor management, the region's gold-bearing deposits were eventually developed into prosperous mining camps.

                    One of the most significant discoveries in Alaska's mining history occurred in the Juneau and Douglass Island district. In 1880, Joseph Juneau, a Canadian miner, staked claims in the area, discovering quartz rich in gold. The resulting mining camp grew rapidly, and the region became known for its abundance of placer gold. The development of these mining districts, along with the creation of a thriving community in Juneau, established southeastern Alaska as a vital hub of gold production.

                    The Treadwell mine on Douglass Island became one of the most successful mining operations in the region. Despite initial skepticism, John Treadwell's efforts resulted in the discovery of a vast gold-bearing ledge. The mine's large-scale operations, supported by significant investments and technological advancements, contributed greatly to Alaska's gold mining industry.

                    However, the ores in Alaska are generally of a low grade, requiring substantial capital investment and advanced mining techniques. The success of operations like the Treadwell mine and others in the southeastern region of Alaska suggests that, with adequate resources, the gold mining industry in Alaska will continue to thrive for the foreseeable future.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1896-03-01/ed-1/?sp=28&q=Alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.88,-0.051,2.76,1.344,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    THE RUSH TO THE YUKON

                    PROSPECTS OF A BIG CROWD IN THE GREAT PLACER DIGGINGS.

                    Parties in Juneau Preparing to Tackle the Range About the Middle of March-One Unusually Early Start-How to Get Into the Basin-Requirements of a Prospector -Stories from the Alaska Diggings.

                    The rush into the Yukon has already begun. The first party of miners to take the trail left Juneau about the middle of January. There were nine men in the party. This is an unusually early start for miners. A good many others in town are getting ready for the trip, intending to tackle the range about the middle of March. Every steamer that comes in from below now brings a party of old-timers and crowds of new men, all anxious to get in and get to work. The Yukon country is almost certain to be overcrowded this summer, surely as regards winter supplies, unless large outfits are taken in from here by the miners.

                    From all accounts received here from sections along the Pacific coast and in the East, Alaska is destined to receive a rush of people this summer which will not be consistent with the present progress and the amount of work now going on. Alaska at present can support so many people and no more, and if the rush pans out according to present prospects there is likely to be considerable hardship. Alaska has no industries except mining at which the wage earner can make a decent livelihood, and unless a man has sufficient means to carry him through, either in some business or for a season's prospecting, he had better steer clear of this country. It requires some capital to prospect for a mining claim, and when the claim is found it requires more capital to open it up. Gold nuggets do not grow on bushes, and it takes both a man's hands and his pockets to get the yellow metal in this country. There's an almighty lot of dirt here, but it isn't to be had for the asking.

                    If you are contemplating making the trip into the Yukon you want to give careful consideration to these things: The length of time you will have to stay in the country, the amount of money it will take, and the results which may be attained. Briefly, these things are: Time, three years; money, $500; results, unlimited. Little can be accomplished in less than three years stay in the Yukon unless the prospector has marvellously good luck. A good part of the first season will be consumed in reaching the mines. Then if a claim is discovered and located only preliminary work can be done. The second year the claim can be opened up well, and probably some money can be made. The third year is when the prospector may reasonably expect to get his profits.

                    No man ought to make the start into the Yukon basin with less than $500 above what he expects to spend for the outfit which shall carry him through to the diggings. That is, if he goes in by way of Juneau and over the pass, he wants to have $500 when he gets to Forty Mile or Circle City, or wherever it is he is going. If he goes by the way of St. Michael's and up the Yukon he wants to have just the same money. The road is a long one whichever way he goes. Supplies are expensive. The season is short, and fortune is fickle. Failure to find gold the first season is likely to entail great hardship upon those whose funds are insufficient at the start. Not one in a hundred makes a paying strike the first season. The trading companies in the interior find a quick market for all their goods at spot cash prices, and they refuse absolutely to give credit. Their supply is almost invariably behind the demand. These are the cold-blooded facts, and if you haven't got the money to meet them you had better not try to go into the Yukon basin looking for a fortune. You won't get it. But if you've got the money, and if you are strong and healthy and ambitious and are a practical prospector, and if you've got good grit, why, come along. Here's the place where you can make a pile. There's lots of it up here, and such men are digging it out every year. It is estimated that they dug out in the Yukon district in the last season upward of $800,000, and that isn't a patch on what's there.

                    The start ought to be made about the middle or not later than the third the middle or week of March, but of course miners do go in as late as May. Parties that start in in March can do their own transporting on sleighs across the summit of the Chilkoot Pass and down the lakes to where good timber for boatbuilding is to be found. The start can then be made down the river when the ice breaks, which is much earlier than on the lakes. In that way the mines may be reached about a month earlier than if the boats are built on the lakes and a wait made for the ice to break there. There should be four or five men in each party. One tent, stove, and set of tools will do for all, if such an arrangement is made. One of the party ought to have some knowledge of boatbuilding for it is an absolute necessity that the boat shall be stanch and substantial. A plain scow of good depth is all that is necessary. It can be easily built, and if it is well done it can be depended upon. No man should attempt to make the journey alone.

                    Nothing can be of so great importance as the selection of an outfit. It is surprising what a very small difference in the quality or fashion of the articles which make up the outfit distinguishes the really excellent one from one which is absolutely valueless for the purpose intended. Too much stress cannot be laid upon this point. The best place for a man who is going into the Yukon to get his outfit is right here in Juneau. The traders here have the benefit of years of experience in furnishing just exactly the outfits that are necessary, and they can beat the merchants below out of sight in getting up outfits as well as in prices. The actual price here is, of course, a little above that in Seattle or Tacoma, but by the time the prospector has got his outfit from below up here, he is sure to find that it has cost him fully as much as, if not more than, a better outfit would cost him here. Hundreds of dollars' worth of goods are thrown away on the trail every year by prospectors who are new to the country and who have bought their outfits down below, only to find that a good portion of their goods is of little value for real service, and only encumbers them in their movements. If you've got the notion that everything in Alaska must of necessity be extremely expensive, you want to remember that there are neither rents nor taxes to be paid up here, and those items consequently do not enter into the cost of outfits.

                    This estimate, of course, may be varied very considerably, and the simple process of multiplication will determine the amounts necessary for larger parties and for longer periods, but too much of any or all of these articles will never come amiss, and too little is only another name for hardship. Enough should be taken to cover any possible delays which may occur at any time by reason of changes in the weather or for any one of many different causes. It is, of course, necessary that nothing should be taken on a prospecting trip which will hinder or impede progress, but it is nevertheless true that every spring finds parties in the Yukon region with scanty supplies, and it is a wise plan for parties to take in with them every ounce of provisions which it is possible for them to carry.

                    The Cook's Inlet territory is much easier of access than the Yukon. It is reached from Juneau by steamer or sailing craft. This place is the outfitting point for all the mining districts of that territory. Strikes were made in the Cook's Inlet country last summer which promise to develop very well this year, and it is possible that the work done there this summer will show the Cook's Inlet country to be a promising rival of the great Yukon district. But the gold fields of Alaska are by no means limited to the Yukon and the Cook's Inlet territory. There is scarcely a spot where auriferous indications may not be found, and to the miner of experience and ability there is no limit to the possibilities.

                    Practically the only development of Alaska which is possible now is in mining, and that is the only opportunity which is offered to outsiders for financial improvement in this Territory. Alaska has all the professional men, clerks, mechanics, and laborers that she will need or can take care of for a long time to come. Mining men with capital, and prospectors who bring a two years' stake, and who can aid in the development of the country are about the only classes to whom the field is open; but to them Alaska offers splendid inducements. Wages here are not as high as is commonly supposed by those on the outside, and the Indians come into competition with the common laborers everywhere. Skilled labor is only fairly paid, and the working seasons are so short that the aggregate earnings are much less than in other climates. Wages of miners in the Yukon country are $10 a day. An outfit complete for the Yukon may be gotten in Juneau for $60; one a great deal better can be had for $150. The fare from the Puget Sound points to Juneau is just now $12 first class and $8 second class. Fare from Juneau to Dyea is about $10; from Juneau to Cook's Inlet is $25. The fare from Juneau into the Yukon by way of St. Michael's is about $175, and board at the stations where stops have to be made will bring the cost up to over $200.

                    The last party out from the Yukon last fall reported that provisions were even then not as plentiful at the posts as they should be, and the river had closed for navigation and no more supplies could come up from the depot at St. Michael's until this spring. Their advice to all going in for this season was to take a full summer's outfit with them. This party went in last spring and found themselves in precisely the predicament which they advised others to avoid this year. They were compelled to move on down the river from the grounds where they wanted to prospect, and had to get their living through energetic hustling, but lost the first half of the working season in the mines.

                    It can be relied upon that the men who are in there now with claims opened up and ready to work as soon as the season opens have all their arrangements made for the summer, and if there is any likelihood of a scarcity of provisions they are not the ones who are going to be caught. The incomers who go there light will have to hustle or move out. For the last eight years each season has found supplies short in the spring. Each year larger and better transportation boats have been put on and their number has been increased, but the increase in the number of miners has fully kept pace with the increase in facilities, and with all that the trading companies have done they have not been able to get ahead of the increasing demands.

                    The last party out last fall brought some reports which it may be of interest to repeat now. Another rich placer strike has been made on Birch Creek, where the best diggings were made last year. The jokers in the diggings named the little tributary of Birch Creek on which the strike was made "Tin Horn Creek," in recognition of the gaming proclivities of the discoverer, but they changed their tune when the prospector took out one nugget weighing $55, and in two days' rocking cleaned up $1,300. The entire length of the creek was located in a very few days after that.

                    On the Pelkey claim the owner set twenty-two men to panning gravel to test the value of his ground. He had them all commence at the same time and pan for one hour. At the end of that time each weighed his proceeds and reported. The highest man on the list had panned out $34, and the sum total for the hour's work of the twenty-two men was a little over $400.

                    The largest nugget taken out last season was on Robert Insley's claim on Glacier Creek. It weighed $234.

                    The main articles of consumption in the Yukon last year were flour and whiskey, the number of pounds of each being about the same. The whiskey was shipped to Forty Mile in bond, and that practically put an end to the smuggling through Juneau and transportation over the pass.

                    Up to the time that the last party left good reports had come in from all points along the river. A lot of new creeks had been struck, and several claims that had been but recently opened up had panned out well. All the old claims were up to the mark.

                    Two men gave six theatrical performances in Circle City last winter and took in $2,300. They put in last summer in getting out logs for an "opera house," which they expected to have completed and in running order for this winter. The principal amusement in Circle City in the winter time is dancing. A miner will go into a dance hall, and balancing the scale with $50 in dust he will get dancing tickets at 50 cents each for that amount. Then the whole house, broken miners and all, fill up the seats until the $50 is gone, when another miner steps up with his long sack of dust and buys a fresh supply of tickets, One of the best strikes made on the Birch Creek diggings last summer was by Jack McGregor, an old Juneau man. He employed about thirty men for the whole summer at $10 a day, and would have paid an ounce a day ($18) if he had had to, to keep the claim running up to the close of the season. He cleaned up $20,000 above expenses. Last spring the stores got out of potatoes, and as a consequence the miners were in danger of scurvy. Jack paid $100 for one sack of potatoes to keep his men in good shape.

                    Circle City bids fair to be the banner camp of the interior. When the last party left, there were 200 houses within the city limits, The most imposing structure had a public hall there were 200 houses within the city limits, The most imposing structure had a public hall.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Six Miners From the Klondyke Tell of the Wonderful Finds of Gold Already Made.

                    A party of six miners direct from the Klondyke reached here yesterday at noon, having come down by rail from Seattle. They are C. E. Myers, B. F. Purcell, J. O. Clements, Charles Leonard, C. Brannan and J. J. Halterman. The stories they tell of the fabulous wealth of the district they have recently left bear out the reports which have been coming in for the past week. They are of the party which came down on the steamer Portland and are the advance guard of twenty-five or thirty of their comrades who are expected here today.

                    Myers, who seems to be the leader of the party, is a practical miner of long experience, and says he left Prescott, Ariz., in the spring of 1896, and has been working claim 30 on El Dorado Creek, owned by McDonald & Chappie, for half the profits. They started in late in the spring, after nearly everyone had quit work, and were laughed at by the miners for so doing. The day after commencing work they struck bedrock, and in the next thirty-three days took out $41,000.

                    Mr. Myers says he believes he took from this claim the biggest pan ever washed in the district. From a shovel half full of dirt he got $800. As illustrating the value of the claim and the richness of the dirt, he also says that his partner and himself in six hours' shoveling "cleaned up" three times, and in each "clean up" got $8,000. Myers owns claim 51 above Discovery, on Bonanza Creek, which he intends to work next season.

                    Another member of the party, J. O. Clements, is said to have disposed of a claim for $50,000, and has in the safe of the Golden West Hotel a nugget valued at $231. The nugget seems to be about half pure gold, and is a very rich specimen.

                    Charles Leonard has been three years in Alaska, one of which has been spent in the Klondyke country. In three and a half months' actual work, he says he took out $14,000. He is going back in the spring, and seems to be very well satisfied with the result of his work.

                    B. F. Purcell is a man about sixty years of age and left his home near St. Louis in April, 1896, bound for the Yukon. He did not reach the Klondyke, however, until the 1st of January, 1897, and while he declines to state the amount of gold he has brought out with him, he says that he sold a half interest in claim No. 28 above Discovery on Bonanza Creek for $21,000, not including the dirt already on the dumps, and says that he is very well satisfied. As he expresses it, the El Dorado and Bonanza Creek districts are a golden wonder, but he is of the opinion that the Stewart River country, which is about eighty miles above Dawson and which was being explored as he came out, will be found to exceed in richness anything yet discovered. He says there is room for 200,000 men in the mining districts of Alaska without any crowding, but that the suffering this winter will be terrible and characterizes any attempt to reach there this fall as foolhardy.

                    Myers says the pay dirt on the claim he has been working is more than 150 feet wide and at least a foot in depth, and that he has never taken out a pan which gave less than $1. On claim 27 in the same district, he says there was a streak eight feet wide and five feet deep which went from $17 to $82 a pan. That claim sold for $50,000, and $200,000 would not buy it today. It is owned by "Big" Alex McDonald and James Doughtry. He tells of a man named Andrew Nelson who made $40,000 for a partner who had given him a grub stake and had never seen the claim. The largest amount brought down by any one member of the party is placed at between $70,000 and $80,000. Myers built the third house erected at Dawson City, and says the discovery of gold in '49 is a mere bagatelle compared to that of the Alaska placers.

                    The men tell harrowing tales of their sufferings and say that the hardships which must be endured in order to exist cannot be exaggerated. Several of the party have not yet recovered from the scurvy, and all appear to be physically demoralized. Their lust for gold, however, is not dimmed, and they are anxious to resume the search for hidden treasure. While wages are very high, said one of the party, a man had much better work a claim on shares, for he has got to make a great deal of money to repay him for going to such a country. Last winter was a mild one, the thermometer only reaching about 70 degrees below zero. During a severe season it frequently goes away down in the eighties.

                    Referring to the amount of dust brought down on the Portland, they say it is impossible to make a correct estimate of the total value, as nearly every man secreted all he could in his personal effects and clothing. Said one: "It would not surprise me to know that two million dollars' worth of dust and nuggets came into Seattle on the steamer."

                    With one or two exceptions, the men intend remaining in San Francisco until ready to start on their northern journey. Going to the mines, the men say the route over the "divide" should always be taken, and in coming out the river route is preferable. One of the men claims to have lost a satchel in which he had over $1,000 worth of walrus ivory, and each of the men has brought down some of the stuff. One beautiful specimen of walrus tusk was shown for which the owner said he paid $5, and which must be worth at least $50 or $60.

                    A member of the party tells of the experience of a man who located the claim adjoining his. This man had been in the Alaska mines for more than five years and had been unable to make a "strike." At last, becoming disgusted with his luck, he resolved to leave the country. On the day before he was to leave Circle City, word reached that place of the Klondyke discovery. He decided to try his luck once more and immediately started for the new diggings. In three months he had taken out more than $20,000 and is still pegging away, resolved to stay until he has $500,000. A man should not, however, say these gold-seekers from the north, remain in the country more than one season without coming to the world of civilization. By coming out, he acquires a new lease of life, as it were, and goes back better qualified to cope with the hardships to which he must submit.

                    "Our greatest privation," said Mr. Purcell, "is the scarcity of fresh meat. A small band of cattle was driven in last fall, and if it had not been for these, I think a great many of us would have died. Any kind of beef brings 50 cents a pound, and at times it is impossible to get it at any price. At an eating-house (it could hardly be dignified by the name of restaurant), two fried eggs generally cost $5, and a square meal would cost more than a day's wages."

                    Charles Brannan owns claim 38 on Bonanza Creek, said to be one of the best-paying properties in that particular district. The patriarch of the party, B. F. Purcell, who is also one of the most enthusiastic, says that there is hardly a foot of ground in either the El Dorado or Bonanza Creek districts which does not carry gold in paying quantities, and that for 300 miles which has been prospected it is the richest country in the world. "I do not believe it would be possible to exaggerate the wealth to be found there," said he, "and the future will add to rather than detract from the marvelous stories already brought from there."
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.89,0.06,2.78,1.354,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    GOLD FOREVER RAGING

                    ALASKAN TOWNS DESERTED IN THE RUSH FOR KLONDYKE.

                    MANY GOING WITHOUT MEANS.

                    MORE STORIES OF THE WEALTH THAT HAS BEEN DISCOVERED.

                    The excursion steamer Queen has arrived from Alaska with 170 passengers, principally tourists. The officers of the Queen state that the merchants and tradesmen in both Juneau and Sitka are closing their shops and hastening to the new Eldorado. Fifty business men left Juneau for Dawson City on July 12, and 150 were to leave on the 15th, two days after the Queen sailed. The officers say that by the time the Queen returns to Juneau on her return trip, nine days hence, there will not be an able-bodied man left in the town. Many men are leaving Juneau for the gold fields without provisions or means to buy them.

                    The steamer Al Ki sailed for Alaska at midnight. She carries forty horses and 1,000 sheep for Dyea, where they will be landed and driven across the summit to the Yukon valley. Stockmen say the sheep are the finest band ever collected off Eastern Washington ranges. They will be taken to Circle City and Klondyke and slaughtered. Any kind of fresh meat there sells at 50 cents per pound.

                    San Diego, Cal., July 19.-An interesting letter telling of the recent trip of the steamer Excelsior to Alaska has been written by Captain J. F. Higgins, of the steamer, to a friend in this city. He says: "The word Klondyke means Deer river, which is called Reindeer river on the charts. It empties into the Yukon fifty miles above the big river. The geographical position of the junction is 26 degrees 10 minutes north latitude, 139 degrees 50 minutes west longitude. Bonanza creek dumps into Klondyke about two miles above the Yukon. Eldorado is a tributary of the Bonanza. There are numerous other creeks and tributaries, the main river being 30 miles long. The gold so far has been taken from the Bonanza and Eldorado, both well named, for the richness of the placers is truly marvelous. Eldorado, thirty miles long, is staked the whole length and as far as worked has paid."

                    "As each claim is 500 feet along the creek bed, there is half a million to the claim. So uniform has the output been that one miner who has an interest in three claims told me that if offered his choice he would toss up to decide. One of our passengers who is taking $1,000 with him has worked 100 feet of his ground and refused $200,000 for the remainder and confidently expects to clean up $100,000 and more. He has in a bottle $212 from one pan of dirt. His pay dirt while being washed averaged $200 an hour to each man shoveling in. Two others of the miners who worked their own claims cleaned up $6,000 from the day's washing."

                    "There is about fifteen feet of dirt above bedrock, the pay streak averaging from four to six feet, which is tunneled out while the ground is frozen. Of course the ground taken out is thawed by building fires, and when the thaw comes and water rushes in they set their sluices and wash the dirt. Two of our fellows thought a small bird in the hand worth a large one in the bush and sold their claims for $16,000, getting $1,500 down, the remainder to be paid in monthly installments of $10.00 each. The purchasers had no more than $5,000 paid. They were twenty days thawing and getting out dirt. Then there was no water to sluice with, but one fellow made a rocker and in ten days took out the $10,000 for the first installment. So tunneling and rocking, they took out $340,000 before there was water to sluice with."

                    "Of course these things read like the story of Aladdin, but fiction is not in it with facts and Klondyke. The ground located and prospected can be worked out in a few years, but there is still an immense territory untouched, and the laboring man who can get there with one year's provisions will have a better chance to make a stake than in any other part of the world."

                    Seattle, Wash, July 19. The amount of treasure brought down from the famed Klondyke on steamer Portland is now placed at $1,500,000, and there is good reason to believe that the sum was nearer to $2,000,000. In this connection, something in the nature of a confidence game appears to have been worked on the North American Trading and Transportation Company, or its officials in charge of the Portland, by the miners. Each man was required to place his gold dust in the ship's safe, but this was not done, by any means. Many of the miners secreted their dust in blankets and luggage, which were taken either to their state rooms or thrown carelessly about the ship.

                    Clarence J. Berry, one of the Klondyke kings, brought down at least $84,000 in nuggets of not a cent of which the Portland had any record. The statement is made on the authority of Captain William Kidson, the master of the vessel. When pressed for an estimate as to the grand total of the Portland's cargo, Captain Kidson said it was no doubt nearer $1,500,000 than the amount accounted for on the ship's records.

                    At present only miners' laws rule the camp, but next year Dawson City will be incorporated and municipal officers elected. The miners are determined on one thing, however, namely, that order will be preserved at all hazards. No "sure thing" gamblers will be permitted in either Dawson City or the diggings.

                    Information comes from Juneau to the effect that several rich strikes have recently been made in the neighborhood of Forty-Mile. It has been christened Minute Creek and is now panning out $22 a day to the men. Another discovery on American creek, fifty miles below Forty-Mile camp, is said to be paying well, and a great number of men have flocked there during the last few weeks. The pans run from $110 to $150. It is thought likely that many of the prospectors will strike for these camps, thus relieving the strain on Dawson City.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-07-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+gold+rush&r=-1.049,-0.093,3.098,1.508,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    THE CALL'S" MAP OF THE ALASKAN GOLD REGION

                    Compiled and Drawn for "The Call" by PROFESSOR GEORGE DAVIDSON.

                    This map of those portions of Alaska and the Dominion of Canada in which public interest is centered has been prepared for THE CALL by Professor George Davidson, who has been for a generation the most competent geographer on the Pacific Coast. Alaska is in the field which for so many years he superintended as the head of the Coast and Geodetic Survey on this coast, and he has been able to supplement the best of the charts yet issued from his personal familiarity with the field and from special sources.

                    This map is a long advance from the best maps hitherto obtainable, and it will not be much improved upon until a long period of exploration and survey has elapsed.

                    This map will be invaluable to those who invade the Yukon region this year and next, and it will long be a valuable reference for all interested in Alaska.

                    The geographical features not charted it is impossible to chart. The latest geographical information about the interior is here given, but years of exploration and survey must elapse before this region is mapped for any distance from the main watercourses. It includes in its showing the magnetic variation of the compass, which it is necessary to know in finding directions by that instrument, as many travelers will have occasion to do. Lines of variation five degrees apart are shown, and arrows indicate more simply the direction in which the needle actually points to the magnetic pole and not the North Pole.

                    The overland route can be readily traced from Juneau to Dyea by water, thence over Chilkoot Pass to Lake Lindeman and Lake Bennett, where boats and rafts are built for the long journey of 600 miles down the watercourse to Dawson. The ride is on through Lake Marsh, through or around White Horse Rapids and to the Lewis River, thence to the Yukon, which is formed by the junction of the Lewis and Pelly at Fort Selkirk. Chilkat Pass and White Pass may be found on either side of Chilkoot Pass, and both may become important routes. The proposed railroad is shown connecting the navigable extremes of Stahkeen River and Feslin Lake in British territory.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-12-19/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    A CHANCE FOR THE POOR MAN AND THE CAPITALIST

                    Alaska is entering upon an era of tremendous development and prosperity in comparison with the past. These new conditions demand new regulations and new laws for her government. Many new propositions will be presented to the coming Congress and many of them will be wild and impracticable. The best and safest proposition for the people of Alaska is to have Congress pass an act allowing the President to appoint a commission of persons who have resided in Alaska and who are well acquainted with its needs and conditions, to draft a code of laws, both civil and criminal, and also to make such changes in the organic act and to establish such courts as may be necessary.

                    From among the hardy, resourceful men who sprinkle gold rushes there will spring to the front brainy ones plenty capable of handling all local questions till the Government steps in. Alaska is in need of such people. They hustle around and force things into line. Alaska has hibernated so long that next spring's awakening will be something tremendous for her. The Indians have a saying: "White man heap fool; take gun and go out hunt bear. Indian take gun and go out and wait for bear." In a rough fashion that has been the character of the country to date. Those Indians are a queer lot to enterprising white men. I remember a mine on Kotzebue Sound; it is a very rich silver mine and the farthest north in this country, where the manager went to San Francisco for the long winter, leaving several natives to watch the plant and the six tunnel mules till spring. When Green got back in July he asked the boss native what kind of a winter they had had. "Oh, fine; heap fine," was the reply. "Heap plenty to eat. Everything heap plenty and fat." They had eaten the six mules.

                    Alaska is probably the most inaccessible country on the globe. To prospect the gold fields requires not only moral courage, but physical strength and endurance. All its approaches are by water. Even the big part of the summer traveling must be done by water, for there is not ten miles of roadway in all of the 600,000 square miles of territory. Even the trails are wretched apologies for footwear. More cattle paths and rough roads were constructed last spring by the pioneer gold rushers than were built by the pelt-hunters and fishers during the preceding 150 years.

                    The coast waters that the gold hunters will be obliged to voyage are frequently visited by sudden storms. The vessels selected for the trips should be of the most stanch and seaworthy kind and should be commanded by experienced and competent navigators.

                    I would sound a word of warning in regard to those old hulks and river boats that are being fitted up for the Alaska trade. I am satisfied that many of them will not reach their destination. If you go by Dyea and the Chilcoot Pass you will have 25 miles of land travel over an elevation of 4000 feet high. If the trip is made in the early spring you must pass over on snowshoes and take the risk of being caught in the blizzards which during that season visit the summits.

                    To me it is a matter of regret that so many people are determined to try to get into this inhospitable country during the coming spring and summer. Thousands of them are going without proper preparation and a sufficient amount of means. There is no question but that many of them will meet disappointment, suffering, and death. It will take years to properly develop the broad Alaskan gold fields.

                    I earnestly advise those who are planned to go and who have not adequate means for a year's camp there to patiently wait until better and cheaper facilities for reaching the Yukon basin are supplied. Companies have been formed to build railroads into the interior from different points on the coast. Several of these companies will no doubt have a railway constructed within the coming year. There is no danger of the crop of mines becoming exhausted within the next twenty-five years. I came to the California mines in 1852. I left in 1854 thinking the mines were worked out. I returned here forty-two years afterward and found that gold-mining in California was only in its infancy; more gold was produced this year than will be produced in all Alaska and British Columbia within the next two years.

                    Once in the gold fields, what are the chances for the poor man and the rich man?

                    Briefly, then, without a proper outfit and supplies, it is absolutely hopeless for anyone to tempt fortune by prospecting. The seasons are so short, living so dear and traveling so difficult that to work for wages practically cuts a man off from aiming at anything higher. With from $500 to $1000 in his pocket, however, a man may reasonably try his chances with the best of the prospectors. Consider some of the difficulties of mining there and you will see why this is so. As far as anyone has dug down the ground is solidly frozen. One miner told me he had sunk a shaft forty-five feet and the ground was icebound ahead of him. Wood cannot be got for less than $20 a cord. The ground must be thawed with fire before it can be picked out. Where wages are $10 a day it costs about a foot to sink a hole. The poor can calculate how long he can hold out to sink a shaft on his prospect at such figures. But capital is going into the country. No doubt it will give employment to a large number of poor men, both in working the older mines and in prospecting for new ones.

                    The gold field is very extensive. I believe that good mines will be discovered north of the Yukon, and that before many years ships will be transporting miners and supplies through Bering Strait into the Arctic Ocean and landing them at the mouth of the Coquille River for the purpose of working the mines on that and other streams which flow into the northern ocean.

                    In the gold mines, the poor man has practically no chance of earning a living. There is no country on earth where he can starve to death quicker. The cold temperature of almost eight months of the year makes it imperative that he shall have a proper amount of food and good clothing. True, the rush of adventurers will develop lines of business that must furnish supplies to the mines, but a limited number of men will fill all such billets. The fish and fur trades already have all the men they can handle. The lumber business cuts but a small figure on account of the scarcity of good timber. Agriculture and grazing will always be very limited. Supplies will always have to come from abroad, and only wealthy companies will be able to handle them in the present rough and expensive conditions of transportation.

                    One point these gold-rushers should bear in mind: In prospecting the practical miner has very little or no advantage over the novice. In that country no person can figure on surface indications while prospecting. Many of the big finds of this last year were in what you might call marshes. No practical miner would have dreamed of looking in such places for gold indications. There is an old saying: "Silver lies in veins and gold is where you find it." Six thousand years of experience has proved the truth of this saying. The chief advantage the practical miner will have over the novice will be in working and developing claims.

                    No man should set foot in the Yukon gold fields without at least $500 in his pocket. That will keep him till he gets work, and in case of a mishap or ill fortune he will have enough to carry him out of the country, for he might as well be shipwrecked on an iceberg in the northern ocean as stranded in the interior of Alaska without supplies.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1898-04-09/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    KILLED ON THE TRAIL

                    Thirty one Miners Crushed Under a Chilkoot Avalanche

                    FIFTY BURIED WITH SNOW

                    LIST OF THE KNOWN DEAD AND INJURED

                    At about noon today, on the Chilkoot trail, between the Scales and Stone House, at least 31 men met death and a large number of others were injured more or less seriously in a snow-slide.

                    The dead were crushed under an avalanche of snow and ice, which came down from the mountain side upon the left-hand side of the trail, about midway between the Scales and Stone House.

                    At this writing, the known dead are: Gus Zebarth, Seattle; Frank Sprague, Seattle; Steve Stevenson, Seattle; Tom Collins, Portland, Ore.; C. P. Harrison, Seattle; W. L. Riley, Seattle; one woman, name unknown; Ed Atwood, New York; C. Beck, Sanford, Fla.; L. Weddlelin, Kansas City; Mrs. Ryan, Baltimore; John Morgan, Emporia, Kan.; Grimes of Sacramento, who has a brother in business at Dyea.

                    Two of the seriously injured are Walter Chappey of New York and John C. Murphy of Dixon, Dakota.

                    BURIED IN THE SNOW

                    Fully 50 people were overtaken by the slide and are either buried in the snow or scattered along the borders of the avalanche in a more or less injured condition.

                    The point at which the accident occurred is some five miles above Sheep Camp. The nearest telephone station is four miles distant. The Scales are some five miles above Sheep Camp. The telephone wires at this point were carried away by the slide. This fact makes it difficult to obtain further particulars at this time.

                    BLINDING SNOWSTORM

                    A blinding snowstorm was raging all day upon the summit, and as a consequence, many of those in the vicinity were making no attempt to travel. Zebarth, Sprague, and Stevenson of Seattle were traveling together as partners, and were found side by side in their bed.

                    Thousands of people were encamped in the vicinity of the accident at the time, and were soon upon the scene, rendering such assistance as was possible. Upon receipt of the news, points below Dyea telephoned up to know if assistance was required, and received an answer to the effect that 5,000 people were at work upon the debris and were only in each other's way.

                    CAUSE OF THE SLIDE

                    All day Saturday and Sunday, a southerly storm, with chinook wind, rain, and snow, prevailed in this vicinity, and it is believed the softening of the snow on the mountain side by those agencies was the cause of the avalanche. The quantity of snow and ice that came down in the slide is estimated at thousands of tons. It swept directly across the trail, which, notwithstanding the unsuitable weather for travel, was thronged with wayfarers. The last vestige of the trail in the vicinity was wiped out of existence, and where it led is now a mountain of snow and ice, under which are many dead bodies that cannot be recovered for days to come.

                    MORE UNFORTUNATES

                    Later reports bring the information that the bodies of three more unfortunate people have been taken from the snow. One is that of Garrison, initials and residence unknown; Ritchie, initials and residence unknown; Durber, initials unknown; residence, Seattle. There was a preliminary slide at 2 o'clock in the morning. People were digging out their goods when the second slide occurred about noon.

                    A LATER ACCOUNT

                    Skaguay, Alaska, April 4 (via Victoria, R. C., April 18). The horror on the Dyea trail is growing in magnitude hourly. As the work of rescue proceeds, it becomes more apparent that many more lives were lost than at first thought possible. It is now believed that between 50 and 100 men and women were killed by the avalanche. Many bodies will never be recovered until the summer sun melts the tons of snow and ice that now bury them from sight.

                    Two or three thousand men are working in relays, as many as can stand side by side shoveling away the debris in search of the dead and dying. Twenty-two dead bodies have been recovered and identified, and 25 have been taken out alive.

                    CORRECTED LIST

                    A corrected list of killed and wounded, as complete as possible at the hour of writing, is as follows:

                    Gus E. Zebarth, Frank Sprague, Steve Stevenson, C. H. Harrison, W. L. Riley, Seattle; E. D. Atwood, New York; C. Beck, Sanford, Fla.; L. W. Weddlelin, Kansas City; Mrs. Ryan, Baltimore; John Morgan, Emporia, Kan.; F. M. Grimes, Sacramento; Mrs. Anna Moxon, Jefferson county, Pennsylvania; Ras Hepgard, Baker City, Ore.; Atkins, Idaho; Tom Geffert, Seattle; E. F. Miller, Vancouver, Wash.; Tom Collins, Portland, Ore.; T. Lamer.

                    The seriously injured so far recovered are: Walter Chappey, New York; John C. Murphy, Dixon, N. D.; Brooke, Portland, Ore.; residence unknown.

                    Railway & Tram company workers who went up the morning of the slide are missing, and it is estimated that 10,000 tons of outfits are buried under the snow and ice.

                    SMALLER SLIDES

                    There were several smaller slides before the death-dealing avalanche was started. About 2 o'clock in the morning, a small slide occurred, which buried several cabins. The alarm was spread, and many people were endeavoring to work back to Sheep Camp when the big disaster occurred. The snowstorm was blinding, and the crowds were coming down by the aid of a rope when overtaken. The exact location of the slide is given as two and a half miles above Sheep Camp, and 100 yards above the Oregon Improvement company's power house. Here an immense gorge rises at a very steep incline into the hills, and it was down this that the avalanche came.

                    ANXIOUS FRIENDS

                    The telephone office here has been thronged all day and night with friends anxious to get some word of friends believed to have been in the disaster. The wires are working well, and information is being gathered here directly from the scene as rapidly as it is collected. Many people have gone from this city and Dyea to Sheep Camp to aid in the work of rescue. It is believed that when the full returns are in, the dead will number nearer 150 than 50.

                    The slide covered the trail for several hundred yards at a depth of six feet in many places. It has effectively blocked travel for the present, and it will be some time before it can be resumed.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1898-04-09/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BURIED BY A MIGHTY AVALANCHE

                    Lives of Scores of Gold Seekers Lost in the Dyea Canyon. 

                    A Wall of Snow Crashes Down Upon a Trail Thronged by Men Bound for the Klondike.

                    A horrible catastrophe, surpassing in the number of fatalities the flooding of the canyon last fall by the mountain lake, has occurred in Dyea Canyon, between Sheep Camp and the Scales. An avalanche of snow and ice yesterday afternoon swooped down the mountain, burying alive and crushing between forty and fifty men, and injuring nearly as many more. There is great excitement at Skaguay and Dyea, and many will leave here for the scene of the disaster on the steamship *Australia*, which sails late tonight for Skaguay. The first news of the calamity reached here at 5 o'clock this afternoon on the steamship *Discovery*, and the *Al-Ki* came in at about 8 o'clock tonight and confirmed the report.

                    The *Al-Ki* left Skaguay at 9:30 this morning. As the fatal snow slide occurred at about 4 o'clock yesterday (Sunday) afternoon, only meager details were obtainable here tonight. The representative of *The Cali* whom I left in charge at Skaguay and Dyea during my absence chartered a tug at Skaguay last evening to take him around the point to Dyea, and from there he will go by horse to the place of death. I will reach the scene tomorrow afternoon.

                    A telephone message was received at Skaguay from Dyea stating that twenty-seven had been dug out of the snow. A large force of volunteers is at work with pick and shovel, throwing aside the snow in the hope that it may be in time to rescue some of the buried men alive. The rescuers worked all night.

                    About 8 o'clock this morning another message came by telephone from Dyea stating that eighteen more bodies had been excavated. If these figures are accurate, they will make a total of forty-three dead.

                    The slide occurred in about the same place where the lake of water broke loose last fall. It was near Stone House and over on the other side of the canyon. John Pellett of Seattle, a passenger on the *Discovery*, left Sheep Camp yesterday morning, a few hours before the snow slide. He said:

                    "The first we heard of the accident was last evening at Skaguay. The report came over from Dyea by telephone. I left Sheep Camp early yesterday morning to catch the first boat south. It had been snowing steadily for two days up the canyon. It was a heavy, wet snow. Great quantities of it accumulated on the mountain sides, and I expected some of it to fall down. There was so much snow that I did not see how it could cling to the sides of the canyon. Great fields and mountains of it were piled upon the top of the canyon on both sides. There are tents and camps all along the canyon. The men go up loaded early in the morning and come back to their camp or cache at Sheep Camp at 11 or 12 o'clock. In the afternoon they make another trip to the summit or the Scales, and along about 4 o'clock and on to 5 o'clock, there is a circular procession of men coming back on the trail. That explains to me why so many were caught and buried.

                    "The walls of the canyon opposite Stone House are almost perpendicular. A man would have only one chance in a hundred of getting out of the way of an avalanche there, even if he looked up and saw it coming. It would be a straight fall instead of a slide. I heard that thirty-one dead men were taken out last night."

                    A little more light is thrown on the disaster by the situation of the trails at Stone House. The horse trail runs to the right of the canyon, going up and over close to Stone House. The foot and handsled trail is over on the opposite side and follows the course of the river, which is considerably lower than the horse trail, and all day long there are twenty men on the hand-sled trail to one on the horse trail. I have seen 100 men on this trail within a distance of fifty yards, going and coming. Nearly opposite Stone House, on the brow of the canyon, is a glacier. Its walls of ice, beautiful as emerald and sapphire in the sunshine, an imaginary cathedral of the skies, stand exposed in June as well as in January. It does not melt away the year round. Mountains of snow crown this glacier during the winter. This is the point from which the avalanche came.

                    A small snow slide which occurred shortly before the big avalanche buried two or three men who were encamped along the trail. While those on the trail were hard at work endeavoring to extricate the unfortunates, the monster avalanche swept down the mountain side, crushing the tents pitched along the trail and enveloping scores of men, the majority of whom were endeavoring to assist those who had met with misfortune in the previous smaller slide.

                    The injured gold-seekers who have been rescued are terribly lacerated, and it is feared that a number of them will die. As soon as the news of the calamity was made known along the trail, men hurried to the scene from Dyea and other points, and with shovels, picks, and even pans and pails toiled to extricate the unfortunates. Sheep Camp was soon left without an inhabitant, as everyone from there to the Scales was soon on the scene.

                    The sight was an awful one, for there in a state of terrible excitement, which increased as the bodies were uncovered, were brothers, fathers, sons, and friends anxiously digging, trembling lest the next body they uncovered should be that of a loved one. As in the rush to the gold fields, but few men, even though traveling together, went to the trouble of inquiring as to the names of their companions, the greater number of the dead have not been identified, and those who have been taken out alive are so benumbed and dazed that they can hardly tell who had been in company with them.

                    The roar of the avalanche could be distinctly heard at Sheep Camp and as far as Canyon City, situated about six miles south of the fatal spot.

                    Seventeen men, all members of the Chilkoot Transportation Company, started over the trail on Sunday morning and had about time to reach the Scales when the terrible slide occurred. None of them have since been seen, and none of their bodies have been recovered. It is feared the entire party was caught in the slide and killed. There were a good many tents covered up beyond the reach of rescuers, and numbers of bodies will never be recovered until the spring sun thaws away their snow graves.

                    At the Stone House, four big slides occurred. One hundred men, who were descending by the aid of a life line 200 yards long, were caught. Of these, only three are known to have been saved. At the Scales, where the third slide took place, at least 100 tons of outfits were covered up. S. A. Townsend of Fort Worth, Texas, talking of the calamity, says:

                    "From personal knowledge and inquiry, it is my judgment that at least 150 people were killed by the slides. When I left Sheep Camp at 10:30 a.m. on Monday morning, thirty-one dead bodies had been recovered, and the number of injured that had been rescued was reported at twenty-five."

                    The dead are being laid out in a tent used as a bunkhouse. Nobody is permitted to touch the remains. Many physicians have gone to the scene from Dyea, and there are about a half dozen doctors at Sheep Camp also; so there is no lack of medical attendance for the injured. There is a well-conducted tent hospital at Dyea. The law authorizes the United States Commissioner at Dyea to act as Governor.

                    A report that the bodies had been robbed lacks confirmation. The United States troops at Dyea would probably interfere to prevent any desecration of that kind.

                    The report that forty-three men had been killed was corroborated by Purser Bush of the *Al-Ki*. One of the men who brought down the first news of the avalanche on the steamship *Discovery* was George Bach, who came from Seward City in February, with the first information of the loss of the *Clara Nevada*, and who is the only person who saw her burn. The work of recovering the dead from the snow continues.
                </text>
            </result>


            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1899-10-15/ed-1/?sp=21&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    NOME'S GOLDEN SANDS

                    MOST WONDERFUL MINING CAMP ON THE FACE OF THE EARTH

                    The most remarkable gold mining at present in the world, if not in the entire history of gold mining, is that now in progress at and about Cape Nome, on Norton Sound, Behring Sea, Alaska, situated about 225 miles north and west of the mouth of the Yukon river, or 135 miles from this point. Gold was first discovered on Snake river last fall, and during the earlier portion of this season, Cape Nome district had acquired considerable repute as a gold producer, and not a few miners from the Yukon river country, many of them stranded here, went over to Nome and either staked such claims as they could get, or secured work as they could find it. Much complaint was made that claims had been taken by persons holding powers of attorney, their principals not being present in person, and in June the Cape Nome district had become so unpopular that reports were circulating to the effect that the whole thing was a "fake" foisted on the public by the transportation companies to improve their business.

                    Whatever of truth there may have been In these stories is now of small import, for in June or early July, some one of the stranded miners tenting on the beach, as the only unclaimed space, accidentally discovered gold in the sand at his feet. He told his story quickly among his stranded friends, and soon all the unemployed were at work on the beach with any and all kinds of tools that would dig. Their success was such that within a few days men who had work on claims along the creek at $10 a day and board threw up their jobs and took to the beach, expecting to earn, and actually earning in many instances, as much in an hour as they had earned in a day.

                    Never had such easy mining been heard of, never had it been found so unexpectedly and so opportunely, and it was not long before everything else was deserted for the seashore, and even women and boys of 10 or 12 years were to be found as busy in the sand as the men were.

                    Since the discovery the number of "beach combers," as they are called, has steadily increased, and today is presented the strange sight of hundreds of miners of both sexes and all ages and conditions strung out along the beach for a dozen miles or more.

                    For miles to the west of Cape Nome the beach runs straight away in a strip of idle land, varying from forty to sixty feet in width between high and low water mark, extending up to the "tundra" or black alluvial soil, which is from three to five feet higher than the beach proper. All of this tundra, and all the territory along the creeks and rivers east and west for thirty or forty miles and back into the mountains for ten or twelve miles had been staked, but on the long strip of tide lands no man had a better claim than another, or could have, under the tide land laws, and here the grand army of gold seekers camped, and in very short order had converted the barren strand into a site of tremendous and enthusiastic Industry. At the same time business of all kinds began to respond to the boom from the beach, and the usual collection of gambling hells, saloons and dance halls went into operation. At present it is estimated that 1,000 to 1,200 miners are at work on the beach, extending west for twenty miles. All these work with rockers, and they occupy just as much territory to the man or group as can work it. It is not unusual for one small square bit of beach to pan out $10 to $15 an hour, but, of course, the space is soon exhausted and the lucky digger must move to another spot.

                    This beach deposit of gold is as yet an unsolved problem. By some it is said that the gold in the sand, which is entirely "dust," has been washed out from the tundra by the waves at high tide and deposited through hundreds of years in the sand. It is found here now from two to five feet below the surface in the drift, and so plentiful that the miner who does not find it in paying quantities is the exception. On the other hand, there are some who claim that the gold is washed in from the sea, and that the real field or "mother lode," so to speak, is to be reached and developed by dredging. There may be something in this theory, but the other seems to be the more tenable.

                    The beach to the east of Cape Nome makes no such gold showing as does the beach to the west, owing to the existence of a long reach of water or "lagoon," which lies a short distance back from the sea and parallel with it. Gold deposits along the creeks in the interior are quite as rich in one direction as the other.

                    The headquarters of the Cape Nome territory is Anvil City-so named from the shape of the mountain above it-at the mouth of Snake river, although Nome City is the postoffice. While the city possesses a number of frame houses, tents are the prevailing shelter, and prices for commodities are pretty much as they are in all mining towns. Notwithstanding this is one of the most accessible mining towns on earth, as ships from any part of the world may come up to its very doors, making due allowances for no harbor and much delay between ship and shore in bad weather. Meals are from $1.50 to $2.50 a bed in a tent, $1.50; plain drinks, 50 cents each: beer, 50 cents per glass, and other things in proportion, including mutton chop at $1.25-and, by the way, these are not much in excess of prices at first-class places in New York city. Copper plate for use in rockers is worth its weight in silver, and one miner who had no copper substituted silver dollars for it, sixty-four of them being required to properly plate his rocker, which, added to the first cost of $20, made it somewhat expensive, even for this locality. Labor in the mines is worth from $8 to $10 a day and board, and even carpenters, about the only other class of labor, are paid $1.50 and hour and board themselves. As the days in summer are from eighteen to twenty-four hours long, a carpenter can put in a lot of spare time. Everybody has money, and as many who have it are not used to it, they are lavishing their earnings by day on gambling, liquor and dance halls at night. Gambling takes the bulk of the dust, and every species of game is represented in Anvil City.

                    As to what amount of gold is being taken out, there is no means of determining. It is known that not more than $200,000 in all have been shipped by steamer, and $100,000 of that has gone out within the past week. The beach mining is reported to be turning out about $30,000 a day, but this in the nature of things cannot continue, and when it is exhausted these men will go to work on the numerous claims lying back from the sea and along the creeks. Here the gold is found in very rich deposits, the claim of Lindeburg & Co., on Anvil Creek, turning out over $1,000 an hour ($25,000 in twenty-four hours), one nugget recently found being worth $312. Another claim, owned by Dr. Kettlesen, in one day cleared up $9,000, and so the stories go. One may hear almost any kind of a fairy tale, and while some of them are exaggerated the fact remains that just now every man in the district has a pocket full of dust and a heart full of hope, and there are no dead-brokes in Anvil City. What the conditions will be a year hence will not be known until then, and cannot be predicted.

                    Nov. 1 communication with the outside world will be completely shut off for seven months at least, and only a few of the people now in the Cape Nome district are fixed with either food or shelter for the severity of the climate, though those who are prepared with houses to live in and sufficient food and fuel can not only pass the winter comfortably, but can do more or less work.

                    There are very few so well off as this, however, fuel being scarcer than food, but among the "beach combers" a novel plan will be adopted. Parties of four, six or eight will organize for winter operations by securing a large tent, spreading it over the ground they propose to work in, and there they will set up housekeeping. The canvas will be protected on the outside from the weather in every way possible, and stoves will be kept going on the inside, so that the tent will not only be comfortable to live and to work in, but it will never freeze in there, and the mining can go on quite as satisfactorily as if the balmy spring were the only season known in the Cape Nome district. A great rush is expected in the spring, but, as has been stated, there are no claims unstaked anywhere within thirty or forty miles of Anvil City, and what lies beyond those limits is practically unknown. But, according to the tales of prospectors, as far beyond as Cape Prince of Wales, 235 miles, gold has been found along the creeks in quantities that would pay from $10 to $50 per man per day if panned by an expert.

                    Claims are offered for sale-a claim being twenty acres-at prices from $50,000 to $150,000, and there are, of course, at this time not many takers at those figures, but they are expected in the spring with the rush.

                    Over 1,000 claims-covering 20,000 acres, about thirty square miles of territory-have been recorded, and it is generally believed that each claim represents a suit at law, so hasty and haphazard have been the methods of procedure in securing claims.

                    The claims of this entire section are of the placer variety, and so far no quartz has been discovered, which means that what is a busy mining camp with millions this year may be a deserted village twelve months later.

                    Nome gold is much darker in color than the gold of the Yukon river country, assaying $19 an ounce, though the current trading price is $16 an ounce. Gold dust and nuggets constitute the bulk of the currency, and gold scales are as necessary in the stores as the ordinary grocer's scales. And gold dust as a circulating medium is not as popular as it might be, for coin or paper money commands a premium of 7 percent in many localities. Such money is known as "chechako," or "newcomer," as only the new arrivals have it, and that is the Eskimo word for new arrivals.

                    Winter at Anvil City that is to say, in the entire Nome district-ordinarily continues from October to June, and a temperature of 50 to 60 degrees below is not unusual. On Dec. 21 the sun barely rises above the horizon, and on June 21 it does not disappear entirely from sight during the twenty-four hours.

                    To the prospective miner in 'the states" expecting to try his luck in the Cape Nome rush next spring it may not be amiss to offer a word of warning that every advantage will be gained by securing one of the patented claims, those in which a townsite has already been established, and in which more favorable arrangements exist for good living, while a much larger percentage of the new arrivals will surely have to go hungry unless they bring their own provisions.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1905-04-02/ed-1/?sp=31&q=Alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    AS SOON as boats are able to navigate the A are inland streams of Alaska, a great summer rush to Tanana is expected to begin. Reports from Seattle state that gold-seekers from all parts of the country are crowding there. A surprisingly large number are outfitting as though they had been in mining regions before and knew how to arrange for the long and tiresome trip by steamer, dog team and afoot.

                    Freight charges from Seattle to Dawson in summer average over $75 a ton, and as much more from Dawson to Fairbanks, so that the cost of taking along an extensive equipment is considerable.

                    It is estimated that the Tanana region produced $1,500,000 in gold last year, when the number of miners was insignificant, compared with the great army that will camp along its streams this season.

                    Before news of the rich finds penetrated beyond the silent forests, pioneer prospectors had quietly taken out a quarter of a million in yellow metal flakes.

                    Until the new trails were broken and in use, Tanana was not an easy section of Alaska to reach or leave, and travelers along that way were scarce, consisting principally of Indians hunting game or stray prospectors nosing about for gold.

                    Situated on the Tanana river, the town of Fairbanks is 150 miles southeast of the point of juncture of that river with the mighty Yukon. Dawson, in the Klondike, is 500 miles away to the eastward by sledge trail, and to the south, Valdez, on the coast, is 564 miles distant.

                    Discoverers of gold along the Tanana were not inclined to shout the glad tidings to the world.

                    Among those patiently washing dirt there during the fall of 1902 was a secretive individual, a Mexican, known as Pedro.

                    Pedro, like the others, lived in a little hut. His bed was a blanket; chairs and table were simply blocks of wood. He had little use for the cabin, except as a place to sleep and store his provisions.

                    All the long Arctic days he searched soil along the streams for gold, usually alone in the vast wilderness. At other places were other men similarly engaged, but they, too, were there for business and had little time for sociability.

                    One day Pedro made a big strike. He found gold that turned out $100 to the pan. Pedro was a rich man. Then he went away to the south. But he didn't spread the news. He was faithful to the miners left behind.

                    Others, too, were lucky. Stray prospectors came that way and immediately located claims. It seemed as if some had smelled the good news from distant camps.

                    For months this handful of men struggled fiercely to wash all the gold they could before the rush began.

                    First to arrive were some steamboat men who had ascended the river with supplies for the trading post just opened at Fairbanks. These men heard of the marvelous new field and promptly staked claims there.

                    Among them was an energetic Japanese named Wada, who, like others of his race, had been in many mining camps of the far North.

                    For some reason, as soon as he had staked his claim and learned of the richness of the region, Wada started out on a long, lone tramp over the snow, with a dog team drawing his supplies, for Dawson, 500 miles away.

                    No trail had been broken, or at least half the distance, but Wada plunged along, helping the dogs and making from fifteen to twenty-five miles a day.

                    He was the first to bear the news of Tanana's wealth to Dawson, and miners of the older Klondike region immediately went wild.

                    This was in the winter of 1904an exceptionally cold season, even in Alaska.

                    Without waiting for spring, miners hurried off in hundreds for a 500-mile journey over snow and ice, and through a roadless wilderness, in a temperature from 50 to 60 degrees below zero.

                    Hastily gathering what supplies they could, some left Dawson in small sleighs drawn by horses, others with dog teams; but the greater number hurried along on foot, drawing their sleds themselves.

                    It was a mad rush for gold: Many reached the new field before spring, but hundreds of others came toiling in all during the summer.

                    When the majority arrived they found the best claims already taken, a shortage of supplies facing them, and discouragement in the air.

                    Wada had returned with the rush. When some of the men realized their position, they organized a miners' meeting and decided to hang the Jap.

                    A rope was found, and Wada was about to be strung up, when he produced a copy of a Seattle newspaper, showing that he had once saved the lives of many whalers ice-imprisoned in the Arctic Ocean by tramping overland from Point Barrow to St. Michael in the dead of winter.

                    This saved his life, but Wada was driven from the region to which he had invited the rush.

                    In spite of their first disappointment, the newcomers spread out and set to work. At this time, gold was only known to exist along one creek. Soon it was found along a dozen creeks.

                    In the spring the rush from Dawson continued by steamboat. Claims were located in every direction. Now, hundreds who arrived late, or who found that their claims did not pay, are working as laborers for the more fortunate.

                    In a little while, too, all the surface gold had been panned, so that it became necessary to work the underground strata by machinery.

                    When the Klondike was struck, the only method known of thawing the frozen ground for sinking shafts and running tunnels was to build wood fires on the surface, scrape away the earth as far as it had thawed, build other fires, and keep this tedious process up indefinitely.

                    Already at Tanana, steam thawers are being used, and steam is also employed to move the windlass buckets that lift the earth.

                    These steam engines and boilers are brought from the eastern United States at great expense. It is estimated that there are now about one hundred and fifty at work in the Tanana region, and many more are expected this spring.

                    Iron pipes with holes in one end inject the steam into the frozen ground. An enormous amount of fuel is required to feed these boilers, and it is estimated that fully one-fifth the laborers in the Tanana country are engaged in cutting and hauling wood.

                    This wood costs from $7 to $10 a cord, and as each camp burns thousands of cords a winter, it is fast becoming scarce.

                    Hydraulic methods of mining will be employed this summer, when the soft surface may be swept away very effectively. Machinery for this work is also expensive, and freight rates to the interior are enormous.

                    The best-paying claims so far located are on Fairbanks, Cleary, Gold Stream, and Pedro creeks. Scattered all along these streams and their numerous tributaries are the homes of the miners.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062014/1936-03-31/ed-1/?sp=2&q=alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.013,0.095,0.991,0.483,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Romantic old mementoes of Alaska's roaring gold rush days, the relics which the late Dr. F. B. Whiting numbered among his choicest treasures, will go under the hammer at Bushell's Auction House.

                    The rifle which Dr. Whiting used to stop the historic strike of railroad workers, and the steering wheel and port and starboard running lights of the old steamer Portland, which brought the first ton of gold from Alaska to Seattle, are among the articles to be auctioned.

                    There is a large collection of Alaskan and Chinese curios and art objects, oriental rugs, furniture for eight rooms, and a four-poster bed in which the present King of England is reported to have slept in while visiting Canada.

                    Dr. Whiting, famed sourdough and surgeon of the Alaska gold rush, was featured by Rex Beach in "The Iron Trail." He died recently at his home in Seattle.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1947-04-09/ed-1/?sp=5&q=alaska+gold+rush&r=0.244,0.084,0.469,0.228,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    There is a new gold rush in Alaska which rivals in enthusiasm, if not in rich strikes, the famous rush of '49.

                    Today's prospectors are soldiers stationed in Alaska. Their gold rush is sponsored by the USO and is classed as off-duty recreation. But that doesn't keep the G.I. "sourdoughs" from hoping to strike it rich.

                    Confronted by soldiers freshly arrived from the United States for postwar duty and demanding "the shortest way to an undiscovered gold mine," the USO leased eight old mining claims near Fairbanks. There the off-duty miners pan for gold and dream of the day they become millionaires.

                    USO hostesses, most of them native Alaskans, drive the soldiers as far as possible over rough mountain roads in station wagons. On the last part of the trip to the claims, the G.I.s have to pack their pans and shovels through the gorges just as the old-timers did.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1923-06-17/ed-1/?sp=19&q=alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Thirteen Washington men this summer will experience the Alaska of gold rush daysthe Alaska of rocky trails and campfires untouched by the comfortable blanket of civilization, which Uncle Sam has thrown over parts of the rim of the Arctic.

                    They are the explorers and surveyors of the United States geological survey and already either have reached Alaska or are en route. They will spend the summer months exploring the oil and mineral possibilities of America's last frontiera frontier stretching far to the northward from the scattered villages where white men live.

                    A party of five will work on the Arctic coast itself. Their task consists of a topographic and geologic survey of the fourth naval petroleum reserve. The party consists of Ney Paige, geologist; William T. Foran and James Gilluly, assistant geologists; E. C. Guerin, cadastral engineer, and Gerald Fitzgerald, junior topographer. Guerin and Fitzgerald will be engaged in the map-making work. The others are there for what they can find and the mineral possibilities of Alaska still are largely unknown. It is not unlikely that new sources of wealth for the nation will be uncovered.

                    Two parties will devote their attention entirely to oil. G. C. Martin, geologist, has been detailed not only to investigate the possibilities of the oil fields of southwestern Alaska, but to make a comparative study of them in connection with the rich California fields. R. K. Lynt, topographical engineer, and W. R. Smith, geologist, will investigate the Cold Bay oil field on the Alaskan peninsula.

                    The oil possibilities of the country have been hardly pricked by explorers, it is claimed, and all the men will be on the lookout for new indications of oil strata.

                    Probably the most formidable task awaits J. B. Mertie, jr. He is assigned alone to a geological investigation of the great Chandaler district in northern Alaska, a country whose possibilities are virtually unknown.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94050093/1947-07-04/ed-1/?sp=3&q=alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.865,-0.16,2.731,1.33,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    SOURDOUGHS TO MEET IN SEATTLE NEXT MONTH

                    Sourdough veterans of the Alaska gold rush will deliver their experiences in memory next month in Seattle where 50 years ago the landing of a "ton of gold" from the Klondike touched off the mass race northward.

                    Plans for the International Sourdough Reunion, Inc., here July 24 to 27 are well under way, officials of the host Seattle Alaska-Yukon Pioneers said this week. The international convention will be Seattle's first since 1942.

                    More than 1500 sourdoughs from the United States, Alaska and Canada are expected to attend the reunion. Invitations have been extended to Governor Ernesting of Alaska, Rex Beach and Robert W. Service, famed for their tales of the north, and George Black, Dawson member of the Canadian Parliament.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045217/1921-04-13/ed-1/?sp=2&q=alaska+gold+rush</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    In the Alaska Gold Rush of 1902

                    When thousands of men rushed to Alaska for gold, it was necessary to ship in sufficient food to last through the long winter months. In such a climate, coffee, when packed in the ordinary way, deteriorates rapidly, but Hills Bros., who originated the vacuum process several years previously, were there with Red Can Coffee, packed in vacuum cans, insuring the Klondikers of having their coffee as fresh and flavorful as when at home.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075284/1928-12-13/ed-1/?sp=7&q=alaska+gold+rush&r=-0.911,-0.018,2.823,1.374,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BUTTE PIONEER TEAMSTER DIES

                    JAMES BROWN WORKED UNDER HUGH KIRKENDALL HAULING SUPPLIES TO UNION SOLDIERS

                    Later He Followed Contractor Into West and Operated Freighting Outfits from End of Union Pacific Line into Montana; Fort Benton Also Freight Center

                    James Brown, 83, pioneer Butte Ing contractor, who joined the Alaska gold rush in 1900, died recently at his home in that city.

                    Mr. Brown was born at Galena, Ill., July 17, 1845. He worked with Hugh Kirkendall, a contractor engaged in hauling supplies to the soldiers of the union, throughout the Civil war. At the close of the war he emigrated westward with Kirkendall. They operated freighting outfits from Corinne, Utah, the end of the Union Pacific railroad, into Montana. Kirkendall established headquarters at Helena, and freighted from Fort Benton, the head of navigation on the Missouri, as well as from Corinne.

                    In the '80s Kirkendall withdrew from the business and Mr. Brown carried on the freighting, concentrating the business in Butte where he hauled supplies to the mines, and ore from the mines to the smelters.

                    In 1900 Mr. Brown joined the Alaskan gold rush. He remained in Alaska from 1900 until 1924, when he returned to Butte on a visit. He stayed here only 10 days, saying Butte was "too crowded" for a man used to the open expanses of the north.

                    Starts Fox Farm

                    In Alaska the hardy pioneer made his headquarters at Bluff City, 52 miles east of Nome, where he operated placer properties. Upon his return to Alaska in 1924 he started fox farming. His illness began last winter at Bluff City and he was removed to a hospital at Nome.

                    Last summer his son, James H. Brown of the Mountaineer Wilding company here, went to Alaska and brought his father to Seattle, where he remained with his daughter, Mrs. Albert Payne, until a month ago, when he was brought to Butte.

                    Mr. Brown is survived by his widow, Mrs. Ida Brown, and his son and daughter.
                </text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
  <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    MANY KILLED BY EXPLOSION

                    Escaping Gas in Boston Subway Works Great Havoc.

                    HALF A HUNDRED INJURED

                    Passing Electric Cars Wrecked and Adjoining Buildings Badly Damaged-Partial List of Dead and Disabled Accident Occurred at Tremont and Boylston Streets.

                    An explosion has just occurred in the subway excavation at the corner of Tremont and Boylston streets.

                    Three electric cars that were passing at the time were wrecked and one of them was burned. Several buildings in the vicinity were more or less damaged.

                    The explosion was caused by escaping gas. Among the buildings damaged are the Hotel Pelham, the Knickerbocker and Head buildings and the Masonic Temple. Window glass in buildings within 200 feet of the scene of the explosion were shattered.

                    At least twelve persons were killed. Four bodies have been removed to undertaking rooms.

                    Forty-two persons are at the Emergency Hospital.

                    Among the dead are: Rev. W. A. Black, professor at Tufts College. G. D. Bigelow, conductor. Unknown man and woman.

                    The injured include James Reardon. John J. O'Connor, Thonsas F. Ford, Mrs. J. R. Wilson, Nellie Jackson, Lucy Dolan, F. W. Teeling, and Mrs. F. A. Peck

                    There seems to be no doubt that at least eight persons were immediately killed. The explosion came just as the street cars were almost in the center of the space at the corner.

                    The first car was in the center when the explosion came. The whole of the wood work, which is used as a bridge over the subway, was lifted into the air, carrying the first car with it and taking along the two horses of the second car. The other vehicles were lifted straight into the air. but came down on the tracks. Instantly the air was filled with flying debris.

                    The first electric car, the one in which most of the killed were riding, no sooner reached the track than it broke in half, and the whole portion immediately burst into flame. Then someone sounded a fire alarm. This brought a large rescue force to the scene, and almost immediately calls were being sent out hurriedly for the ambulances.

                    It was an awful sight that met the gaze of those who were first on the scene. In the center was the long blazing electric car. Close beride this were the bodies of the two horses killed instantly, and about ten, twenty, thirty feet away from where the woodwork of the car was blazing lay the dead and wounded people. Those who were not injured in the cars on Boylston street were Incapable of action at first, and people in the buildings and stores surrounding did not know what had occurred, but it did not take them long to secure their senses, and almost immediately there was a rush to the assistance of the wounded.

                    It is stated that there was not a person on the three cars who was not injured, and all the wounds received were severe. Immediately stores and offices were converted into temporary hospitals until ambulances could arrive. It was a gruesome spectacle to see these bodies exposed on the sidewalks.

                    Hose carriages were pressed into service as ambulances, and immediately they were started on their humane duty of getting the maimed to the hospitals.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&q=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway&r=-1.275,-0.05,3.55,1.729,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.

                    THE BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COMPLETED AND IN OPERATION.

                    A BRIGHTLY LIGHTED TUNNEL AFFORDING RAPID TRANSIT FOR ELECTRIC CARS CONGESTION OF THE STREETS RELIEVED.

                    The subway for streetcars in Boston, a part of which has just been opened for service, is an enterprise of more than local interest. The necessity for some relief to the crowded thoroughfares above it can best be appreciated, of course, by Bostonians; but the Modern Athens is by no means the only city in this country which is beset with problems of the same character.

                    Those who are familiar with "the lay of the land" in Boston remember that Tremont-st. runs in a generally north-and-south direction and forms the eastern boundary of the Common. It is intersected by Boylston-st., which constitutes the southern boundary of that historic park. On the Boylston and Tremont st edges of the Common there is a broad promenade, known as the Mall. The main part of the subway, which is wide enough to accommodate four tracks, passes under the Tremont-st. Mall, and, after passing under Park-st., which lies along the northern side of the Common, extends (or will extend, when completed) to Scollay Square, thence eastward to Adams Square, and finally up northward again to Haymarket Square. This terminus is close to the great union railway station at the North End.

                    From the corner of Tremont and Boylston sts. there are two extensions, wide enough for only a double track. One runs westward under Boylston-st. Mall for about 300 feet, and then ascends an incline through an open cut for 318 feet. The terminal station for this branch is situated in the Public Gardens. The other branch reaches away to the southward, and, on nearing the junction of Shawmut-ave, and Tremont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline leads up into each of those streets.

                    Including the inclines, the subway has a total length of about a mile and a half, and will contain about five miles of track. At present the branches from the corner of Boylston and Tremont sts, and the main line up to Park-st. are in operation. A great deal of work has already been done on the northern portion of the route, and it is hoped that everything will be finished within the next eight months. Ground was broken for the subway in April, 1895, twenty-nine months ago.

                    The depth of this underground passageway is 14 feet. The width is 24 feet for two tracks, and 48 feet for four. At intervals of six feet, along the sides, steel posts are set up on good foundations, and from the tops of those on one side there reach across to the tops of those on the other steel roof beams. Where there are four tracks there is a central line of posts in the tunnel, in addition to those along the sides. From one cross beam to the next there extends an arch of masonry. These successive arches, forming the roof, are covered with concrete, and the same material fills the space between the posts along the sides. A waterproof backing of asphalt assists in excluding from the subway water that might otherwise leak in from the soil. The masonry floor is hollowed, like an inverted arch, and along its central line there runs a drain. At intervals the drain discharges into a pit, from which, whenever the water rises to a certain level, the contents are withdrawn by automatically controlled electric pumps.

                    Ventilation is effected by huge rotary fans, established in masonry chambers at three or four points along the line. The air is sucked out of the subway, and forced upward through the openings to the level of the street. Hundreds of incandescent electric lamps and scores of arc lights are disposed advantageously along the interior. As electricity is also employed for the propulsion of the cars which use the subway, there is no smoke to accumulate on the ceilings, and no foul gases to offend the olfactory nerves, There is no reason why the place should not remain clean, sweet and bright for years.

                    At the underground stations, of course, the subway is broadened. A high wire fence runs lengthwise in the middle, separating the two northbound tracks from the two southbound. The tracks of each pair are divided by what engineers call an "island platform," say 30 feet wide, and 300 or 100 feet long. Access can be had to one platform from the other only by going down a low flight of stairs and through a narrow but brightly illuminated passage underneath, or else going up to the street and crossing over.

                    The cars which run through the tunnel are ordinary trolley-cars, but, like many which traverse other routes in the city, they are all controlled by one corporation, the West End Street Railway Company, to which, by the way, the subway has been leased by the Transit Commissioners. This fact partially explains some of the precautions taken at the stations. There one buys a ticket before boarding a car, or getting a chance to do so, and the conductor on the car collects the tickets. Exit from the station platforms is effected through turnstiles, which allow a person to pass in only one direction.

                    Broad, easy stairs lead down from the street to the underground stations. There are seldom more than thirty steps in a flight. There are two flights for the northbound tracks, and two for the southbound. The head of each staircase is enclosed by a neat one-story, glass-roofed granite building. Glazed white brick and plenty of white paint impart to the station interiors a fresh and cheery appearance. At present the only stations in use underground are at the corner of Boylston and Tremont sts. and at Park-st. A temporary loop at the latter point permits the northbound cars to return without switching. When the subway is completed, however, there will be other stations at Scollay Square, Adams Square and Haymarket Square.

                    Only an engineer can begin to understand the difficulties of an undertaking like this. Countless sewers, water-pipes, gas-pipes and telephone wire conduits have been laid close to the route, and some of these have been bared during the progress of the necessary excavation. When their position was at a higher level than the roof of the future subway it was not necessary to do more than to protect them carefully for the time. But if they were lower than the roof, and higher than the floor, the situation was more serious. Two great water mains, one thirty inches in diameter and the other forty inches across, were encountered at that very inconvenient level. It became necessary to construct siphons, bending down under the subway and up again on the other side, in order to adjust these conflicts of interest. For the happy solution of all these difficulties great credit is due to the City Commission entrusted with the work, to their chief engineer, and, in some measure, to the engineers of the West End Company.

                    An incidental but important feature of the plan of construction is the avoidance of grade crossings. In the four-track passageway the Boylston-st. cars have the two inside tracks, and the Tremont-st. and Shawmut-ave. cars use the two outer ones in common. Accordingly, at the southeastern corner of the Common, the westernmost track (southbound) is carried down under the two central ones, by a special one-track tunnel which soon emerges with another one-track tunnel carrying the up-track. At a point still further south a similar plan is pursued in the separating of the Shawmut-ave. and Tremont-st. cars.

                    The capacity of the subway is ninety cars per minute. Inasmuch as the facilities thus afforded are supplementary to those already afforded on Tremont-st., and are not a substitute for the latter, a distinct increase in the number of routes, as well as freedom from blockades, has been secured.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE STREET CAR PROBLEM.

                    Congestion of Traffic In the Busy Streets of the Hub Relieved by Underground Trolley Lines-Tunnels That Are Light, Clean and Attractive.

                    It is now possible to cross Tremont street, Boston, at any point opposite the Common and at any time of day without loss of life or limb. The new subway has brought about the change.

                    It is an old tradition that the fathers of Boston, when they laid out the city, let the streets follow the winding cow paths. At any rate, the streets as they exist today are very crooked and most of them are very narrow. This was all right in Revolutionary times, but when the city grew miles beyond the Common and spread itself out to the south and west; when business centered itself along the lower ends of Washington and Tremont streets, and when dozens of street car tracks usurped the narrow roadways, then the Bostonians wished their ancestors had not stuck so closely to the cow paths.

                    Probably no other city on the continent was ever so badly afflicted with a congestion of traffic as the Hub has been for many years. Some of the most important street car lines skirt the south and east corners of the Common on Boylston and Tremont streets. When the change was made from horsepower to trolley, matters grew worse. Then the poles and the tangle of overhead wires made that historic breathing spot look like a piece of dingy, green billiard cloth which had become frayed and tattered around the edges. So after much wrangling in the legislature and courts it was decided to build the subway and put the trolley cars underground.

                    A large portion of the work has already been accomplished and Boston is delighted with the result. The first thing a Boston man asks a visitor from New York, Chicago or elsewhere is: "Been through the subway yet? Let's seeyou haven't one in your place, have you?"

                    It is, in fact, a triumph of engineering and well worth a visit. There are three open cuts where the trolley cars enter the subway. One is out on Tremont street where Shawmut avenue comes in. Here the tracks from each of those thoroughfares dive into the tunnel. Another is in the Public Gardens, where the cars coming down Boylston street take the underground dip. The third is at the northerly end of the subway, just beyond Haymarket square and in front of the new Union terminal railroad station into which the Fitchburg, Boston and Maine, Eastern and other roads run. There is a loop here as most of the trolley lines make it their terminus, and, the subway being four tracked, they disgorge their passengers and take the back track uptown.

                    Including the inclines or open cuts, the subway has a total length of 14 miles and will contain about five miles of track. At present the branch down Boylston street along the Common side and the main line down Tremont to Park street are in operation. The Shawmut avenue branch and the northerly end of the main line will be finished within the next eight months. Ground was broken for the subway in April, 1895. The sum appropriated was $7,000,000 and, wonderful to relate, the transit commissioners say that it is probable the cost will be about $1,000,000 less than that sum.

                    No great difficulties have been encountered thus far in digging this big hole in the ground. Of course there were countless sewers, water pipes, gas pipes, electric wire conduits and the like and some 40-inch water mains at an inconvenient level proved rather hard to handle, but no unexpected conditions arose to delay the work. The main trunk of the subway runs under the wide walk or mall on the east side of the Common, and when the excavations were being made the bones of hundreds of old Puritans were disturbed. This raised a howl of righteous indignation, and the sacredness of the long forgotten burying ground was harped upon for weeks. But the commissioners quieted the reverent patriots by collecting all the bones and reinterring them in the holy ground of the Common, with a nice monument to mark the spot.

                    The deepest point of the subway is on Boylston street, where the southbound tracks are laid 39 feet below the surface, but the average depth is 14 feet. The tunnel itself is a giant bore with ribs of steel and casings of cement, asphalt, concrete and masonry. The roof is a series of arches and the floor is concave, with drains at the bottom. As the drains are below the level of the sewers, pits have been established at intervals, and when they are filled with water automatic electrical pumps are started, which empty them into the sewers above.

                    Perhaps you imagine that Boston's subway is a dark, damp, ill-smelling place. It is nothing of the sort. The entrances to the stations are handsome structures of stone, with glass roofs. The only fault to be found with them is that they remind one of something one thought of the first time they saw one. But then you go down an easy flight of wide stone steps to a cheerful, brilliantly lighted station. Everything is dazzlingly white. The bricks lining the entrance are of glazed white porcelain, the masonry arches are painted white and the iron pillars and supports are covered with immaculate white enamel. Incandescent and arc lights flash everywhere, and the vista ahead through the stretches of the subway is far from a dingy one. It is about the cleanest and neatest hole in the ground in existence and no doubt will be kept so. Already the traffic on Tremont and Boylston streets has been much decreased, and when the subway is fully completed Boston folk may get about their town with comparative ease and safety.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/?sp=3&q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    UNDERGROUND TRANSIT A FAILURE IN ACTUAL PRACTICE

                    People Refuse to Een It, Just ne They Wanld the Stole in the Ground Transit Proposed for New York-Only Beven Per Cent. of the Total Trame Credited to the flubway-The Profitable Fancy Traffle Lest to It Entirely -Yot the Conditions Are Most Favorable Boston Wants as Elevated Ratirend Now,

                    Before any further attempt is made to com- sait this city to the building of the proposed underground system of rapid transit it would be well for every one interested to learn some- thing of the experience which Boston is now having with its subway. Boston's subway is New York's proposed underground railroad in miniature, except that it was constructed for the use of the trolley car lines instead of being equipped with cars, motors, and power of its own, and running two sets of trains-one express and one local.

                    The Boston subway is short. That part now in use is less than a mile in length, and the parts which are under construction or proposed would add only about another mile to the tunnel. There is, perhaps, no finer specimen of passenger tunnel work anywhere in the world, and it is doubtful if any more perfect tunnel could be constructed.

                    The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and Its extensions are to go under Cornhill, Hanover street, and Washington street, passing right through the dense business and shopping districts, and thus securing every advantage that a road might have if it ran through Broadway, Fourteenth street and Twenty-third street, and part of Sixth avenue. And yet, in the face of all these advantages, three months' experience has shown that the Boston subway is not popular, that people will not go into it except when they have to, and that the subway is a failure, save so far as it was a necessity to relieve the congestion of traffic on the street.

                    Bostonians are proud of the subway. They take strangers to see it, just as they take them to see Bunker Hill Monument; make them ride the length of it back and forth, and call attention to all its fine features and then they keep away from it themselves, just as they do from the monument. That this result is of interest to New Yorkers there can be no doubt. The building of the subway grew out of a public need which was as absolute and pressing as the need of this city for some addition to its traffic facilities.

                    When, about ten years ago, the West End Street Railway Company began to transform the old horse car lines of Boston into electric trolley lines, the narrow streets in the heart of Boston were already choked with the daily rush of vehicles. Boston has today the most extensive and comprehensive electric car system in the world. The added cars which were required for the new service fairly filled the streets of the little central city where they were all concentrated. These car lines serve a suburban population of nearly a million persons, and it is possible to take a car for any part of the territory covered without going more than a quarter of a mile in the city. Under a special act of the Legislature, the Boston Transit Commission was appointed to devise a suitable means to relieve the congestion.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Riding Astride Makes Little Headway Among Ladies

                    There is a rumor that the bean-eating, blue-blooded Boston dames have mounted a new hobby. They ride astride. Not the hobby, but the horse. They think this is a good time to begin, says the New York Sun, Since the Boston subway was completed, a large part of the population spends its time underground, riding back and forth through the tunnel and exclaiming: "We did It!"

                    This has increased the above-ground inhabitants to so small a number that It's a good time to overcome public opinion, because there's so little of it to overcome. Consequently, the Boston women referred to have seized the chance to establish the new fad in riding. They know that by the time the people get tired of looking at their hole in the ground, bloomers will have become a part of the Boston creed of B's. It's growing. Already it includes Boston beaus, Boston bays, Boston blue blood, and Boston bas bleus.

                    Within a few weeks, the same rumor has broken out nearer home. Newspaper paragraphs have declared that New York women, too, are going to abandon the side saddle and take to divided skirts. Doctors who have been consulted sigh and say they only wish the rumor would come true. They do what they can to push it along. They prescribe riding astride, and say it is the only healthful and safe way for anybody to ride. But they say that it's one of the prescriptions which New York women have so far declined to take.

                    And yet there is a persistent rumor in the air that women have been seen riding astride even in the park. The regular policemen have a certain reputation for blindness, but there is no particular reason why a park policeman should have trouble with his eyes. He ought to know if there are any visions of amazons in divided skirts fitting along the bridle paths there summer days. Several policemen were, therefore, approached on the subject,
                
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42&q=BOSTON+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Historic Landmarks and Crooked Streets Disappearing.

                    Within three years the crooks and turnings and devious wanderings of Boston's most honored highways and byways will be nothing more than a memory of the past, and many of her ancient landmarks will be wiped out or so altered as to be unrecognizable to the oldest inhabitant. Slowly and surely the ancient thoroughfares are being widened, straightened and bent into the rulerlike lines of crosscut New-York, Philadelphia and Chicago. Boston is undergoing a transformation below and aloft that would cause Benjamin Franklin, John Hancock, Warren and Paul Revere to rub their eyes and stare in amazement. Million dollar buildings by the dozen, elevated roads, tunnels and streetcar lines beneath the streets and under the harbor, swamps and mud flats filled in for piers and excavated for docks that accommodate giant steamers-these are the things they would see.

                    Along State-st., beneath the spot where the Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the historic old State House, a tunnel is eating its way from under the harbor to Scollay Square to connect with the present subway by means of flights of stairs and elevators, and thence outside to the busy world. The old State House itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station connecting with a subway line also. The remodelled building will soon be crowded with people hurrying back and forth, intent on business, with never a thought of its old associations. Little do they think, as they hurry past where tunnel workmen are digging seventy feet beneath, of what has happened in that quaint old edifice. On this site the first State House was built in 1657. Destroyed by fire in 1711, it was rebuilt in 1712, and rebuilt again in 1747, when destroyed a second time. The building has been in turn Town House, Courthouse, Province House, State House and City Hall. On the first floor in the early days was the merchants' walk, or exchange.

                    During the Stamp Act excitement the stamped clearances were burned in front of its doors. The British troops were quartered within the building in 1768, and the Boston Massacre occurred about fifty feet away on March 5, 1770. The next day Samuel Adams stood in the council chamber and made his successful demand upon the royal representatives for the immediate removal of the British troops from Boston. In this same room Generals Clinton, Howe and Gage held a council of war just before the battle of Bunker Hill. In 1789, at the western end of the State House, Washington reviewed the great procession in his honor on the occasion of his last visit to Boston. Here, also, in 1835, William Lloyd Garrison found refuge from a mob which had broken up an anti-slavery meeting, and threatened his life.

                    The Park-st. station of the present subway handles 27,000,000 passengers a year in the course of its trolley traffic, but the number of passengers who will pass through the old State House station will far exceed this number.

                    The march of progress does not stop here, however. Down Washington-st., to connect with the tunnel and present subway, will be another subway, this a double one for elevated trains after they leave the surface at the Broadway extension. It will pass beneath the Old South Church, the Old Corner Bookstore and other well-known landmarks. Through the tower of the Old South Church, which juts out into Washington-st., it is planned to cut an arcade, in the general scheme of widening and straightening Washington-st. Surrounding the Old South Church on three sides, a new $1,000,000 office building eleven stories high is going up rapidly. The Old South Church has been called the "Sanctuary of Freedom." The ground on which it stands was formerly the site of Governor John Winthrop's home, where he died in 1649. The land was afterward owned by Mme. Mary Norton, wife of the Rev. John Norton, who gave it in trust "forever, for the erecting of a house for their assembling themselves together publicly to worship God."
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>
                
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/?sp=4&q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    East Boston Tunnel, Just Opened, Runs Under Harbor.

                    Boston, the pioneer city of America in subway construction, now boasts a subway said to be the greatest single boring yet completed under the water of a river or harbor. It is the East Boston tunnel, extending from the "city proper" under the harbor to Maverick square, East Boston. It is the second subway to be opened in Boston, was begun in 1900, has cost $3,000,000 and has just been turned over to the Boston Elevated Railway company for operation. It is about one and two-fifth miles in length and has an exterior diameter of nearly thirty feet, though the thickness of the walls brings its interior diameter down to about twenty-four feet.

                    The East Boston tunnel runs to a depth of more than ninety feet below the waters of Boston harbor through a blue clay sediment. It is for the use of regulation trolley cars, which come to the surface at the suburban end of the passage and continue their journeys over the street tracks. Eventually the tube will be connected directly with the present subway in Boston's congested district.
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023296/1906-06-09/ed-1/?sp=1&q=bomb+Bomb+Boston+explosions+FIRE+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Lives Imperilled in Boston's Underground Railway.

                    Terrific Explosions Caused by Short Circuiting of Heavily Charged Electric Wires-Hundreds of Men and Women Thrown Into Panic-Three Persons Injured.

                    A blast of a charge of dynamite under tons of granite, and clouds of black, sickening smoke belching forth, threw hundreds of men and women into a panic and paralyzed traffic in the subway at the Boylston street station at 5:30 o'clock, Wednesday afternoon.

                    No one knew the trouble. Elevated road employees and officials were alike confused, and fearful of what might come next, as the smoke rapidly filled the stations at Boylston and Park streets, and passengers were rushed from the cars to the surface.

                    Attempts to call the fire department found the telephones so charged with electricity as to be useless.

                    Many of the women reaching the subway by the Boylston street cars were overcome by the smoke, fainted, and had to be dragged to the surface. Several became hysterical and were controlled with much difficulty, the danger being constant of someone falling from the platforms overcome by the smoke and becoming electrocuted upon the deadly third rail.

                    Trainmaster Benjamin was the first official to reach the Boylston street station and to bring some sort of order out of the chaos. Entering the subway along the line of the northbound cars, he made his way some 100 feet to the south of the station and found the cause of the trouble.

                    The feed cables for the third rail, running between the rails and enclosed in four-inch wooden box conduits, were found grounded and throwing off flashes of electricity, which illuminated the subway for many hundreds of feet. The electricity had jumped to other cables running parallel, and even charged the walls of the subway. Ten powerful cables felt the influence of the cross and were cracking and throwing off flames and flashes of light, threatening death to anyone who came near.

                    The wooden box conduit, black and greasy and very inflammable, was burning rapidly. A northbound train which had passed over the spot caught fire and was pulled back to Pleasant street, blazing fiercely underneath. The terrified passengers were hurried off at Pleasant street, and the fire beneath the curb was extinguished by road employees before serious damage was done.

                    Three persons were hurt, and all of them were on the surface. The accidents which caused their injuries were the direct result of the trouble in the subway. The injured were all near the Pleasant street entrance to the subway and were hurt by the explosions in three manholes at that point.

                    Trainmaster Benjamin ordered all trains into stations, and then the current on the third rail and feed cables was shut off.

                    Chief Mullen and the fire department had been notified before the power was shut off and entered the subway at the Boylston street station, although there was great danger for anyone, however familiar with the subway, to enter in the dense smoke which filled every foot of space between the walls.

                    As Chief Mullen's men touched the walls, they felt a shock at once. The brass nozzle of the chemical hose they carried became charged, and with electricity running up their arms, the men hesitated for a minute for orders from their chief.

                    "I'll risk it," shouted Chief Mullen, and he dashed into the smoke-filled subway. His men followed close behind, their hands on the shoulders of the men in front. A few daring newspaper men brought up the rear.

                    Half an hour was consumed in putting out the flames, which had followed along the box conduits nearly 300 yards.

                    Both Chief Mullen and Assistant Chief Brady termed it one of the most dangerous fires they were ever called upon to handle, not from its intensity but for the dangers of electrocution that surrounded them and the thickness of the smoke.
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/?sp=30&q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BOSTON'S SUBWAY, SURFACE AND ELEVATED LINES PRACTICALLY TIED UP BY STRIKE

                    By noonday the surface, elevated and subway car system of Boston and suburbs was utterly disorganized.

                    A strike of the union employees of the Boston Elevated, which controls the surface and subway lines, was called at 4:15 o'clock this morning after a stormy three-hour session at union headquarters.

                    The elevated officials laughed at the strike. When the union was formed only a few weeks ago the elevated set about a counter organization, a "protective" association they called it.

                    This morning the officials of the company claimed they had 2,000 men in this protective association who would continue to work, and that they had 1,500 strike-breakers already imported up from New York and Philadelphia.

                    There was a good deal of rioting after the strike was called. Cars were stoned, trolleys disconnected, motormen and conductors who refused to recognize the strike order roughly handled, sleepers were put on the tracks, and cautious Bostonians walked to work this morning.

                    But the rioting never became very serious and it was not necessary. As the forenoon wore on, motormen after motormen, and conductor after conductor left their packed cars standing in the street and went to union headquarters to report.

                    Even where they did not leave the cars there always was someone to disconnect the trolley wires. Then the motormen and conductors would refuse to get off to fix it, and the police would have to do it.

                    Because the guards at the Park street terminal of the Cambridge subway reported to the union the escalators were stopped and passengers had to climb three flights of stairs to the street.

                    There are 3,800 members of the union. The strike was called because:

                    The company refused to recognize the union; announced it would employ no union men.

                    When complaints were made against men, they were laid off without pay pending a hearing.

                    Conductors were forced to furnish $10 change for each trip.

                    Despite the company's refusal of an increase because their "finances would not stand it," the "loyal federation or protective association" members' pay was increased when the union was formed.

                    Police Commissioner O'Meara ordered all the reserves on duty at the subway and elevated stations and car barns this forenoon. There already have been fifty arrests, but all the cases were continued until Monday.
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90005351/1921-12-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    EXPLOSION SCARE IN BOSTON SUBWAY

                    23-Traffic was paralyzed for two hours, thousands of commuters and Christmas shoppers frightened in underground train when a main power cable in the Cambridge subway grounded and exploded, thus shutting off the current. Confusion broke loose in the vicinity between Chauncey street and the South Station when volumes of black smoke poured through the tube and permeated to adjoining subway systems. The officials of the road declare that there were no injuries resulting from the accident.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020358/1897-02-11/ed-1/?sp=5&q=boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BOSTON'S FAMOUS SUBWAY

                    CHIEF ENGINEER CARSON TELLS HOW IT IS CONSTRUCTED.

                    Lecture Before Engineers' Club-Features of the Engineering Work on the Subway -Subways in Other Cities.

                    An exceedingly interesting and valuable lecture was given last evening in North Sheffield hall by Howard A. Carson, member of the American Society of Civil Engineers and chief engineer of the famous Boston subway. The lecture was given under the auspices of the Engineers' club and was largely attended by citizens as well as students.

                    Professor DuBois introduced Mr. Carson, who spoke on "Subways in Boston, London and Elsewhere." The lecture was illustrated by stereopticon views of the Boston subway and also of some of the European subways which Mr. Carson has visited.

                    The lecturer at the commencement explained why the Boston subway was built. "The population of Boston 130 years ago was less than 22,000; 100 years ago about 26,000; In 1830, In the remembrance of many, about 82,000, while today the city has about 500,000. The population of Boston doubles in about thirty-five years.

                    "The use of the streets for travel increases faster in proportion than the population of the city. In 1896 167,000,000 persons were carried by the street railways. While the population doubles only in twenty-five years, travel on the street railways doubles in about ten years.

                    "The streets are no wider now than they were one hundred years ago, and they are not able to do the work they are needed to do. If streets can't do the work required of them the natural thing to do is to build them wider or make new streets, but the cost is too great for this. Perhaps $100 a great for this cost. If you broaden the old streets, you must do the way a person does when a house is overcrowded and has not land to build newby adding stories to the old. In the case of a street, you have to decide between an elevated way or a subway.

                    "The mere cost of erecting an elevated road is only about one-half or one-third of that of a subway, but the damage which has to be paid to adjacent property owners makes the cost of the two systems about the same. As to the convenience and comfort of the two methods, different persons are likely to hold different views."

                    Mr. Carson then explained an elevated road which is being constructed in Germany, where the cars are suspended from the track instead of running the rails.

                    "The Boston subway is being built under some of the most traveled streets of the city. For most of the distance, it is to have two tracks, but at points there are four tracks where the cars can run back without running to the end of the line. At the northern end, there is an incline where the cars can come to the surface. Stations for passengers are placed at convenient distances, usually one in about 1,000 feet.

                    "The retaining walls of the subway are of granite and concrete, mostly of concrete. There are two forms of construction employed in the roof, one made of steel and concrete and the other the brick arch.

                    "The subway is about twenty-four feet in width at the incline, where there are two tracks, and about sixteen feet high. In the middle of the subway, there are brick walls with open joints, so that the water can easily find its way into it, and the top is covered over with flags easily removed if the drain needs inspection or repair.

                    "At the passenger stations, there are two stairways, each fifteen feet in width. It was not intended at first to use elevators at all, but it may be thought desirable to adopt them at some stations later on.

                    "In the work of construction, many pipes were encountered which had to be removed or passed under. The work is being so performed as to cause the least possible hindrance to travel on the streets. In the daytime, one-third of the street is occupied for the plant and material used for the work, and the other two-thirds is left for travel. At night about two-thirds of the street is occupied in the work.

                    "Bridges are built over the excavations on a level with the street, so that one passing over them will hardly notice the fact. The work is done by what is known as the slice method, by which ten or a dozen sections are being excavated at the same time, no two being adjoining.

                    "There are eight fans placed at appropriate intervals to ventilate the tunnel, each fan being seven feet in diameter. It was feared by some that the excavations would weaken the foundations of some of the high buildings, but the work has so far advanced now that there is seen to be no danger."

                    Mr. Carson closed his lecture with a rapid description of subways in Budapest, Paris, London, and Glasgow, and also a description of the use of the shield in tunnelling.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1902-06-28/ed-1/?sp=12&q=boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BOSTON SUB-WAY BILL.

                    The Boston sub-way bill, generally referred to as the Washington street sub-way bill, was signed by Governor Crane at 5.49 this afternoon. It had been enacted in the House an hour before, Its provisions are subject to ratification or rejection by the voters of Boston.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015415/1898-02-09/ed-1/?sp=5&q=boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BOSTON'S SUBWAY.

                    The Boston subway work is nearly completed. According to present prospects the total cost of the improvement will fall considerably within the engineer's estimate. The total cost of the subway to date is 4,043,313. The original estimate was $5,000,000. A tunnel under the harbor to East Boston is again being discussed.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1906-06-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    ELECTRIC PRANKS IN THE BOSTON SUBWAY.

                    Three Injured, Firemen Shocked and Traffic Held Up for Two Hours.

                    Cables Short Circuited and Subway Filled With Dense, Choking Smoke.

                    Trouble Occurs Corner of Boylston and Tremont, Scene of the Disaster of March, 1897.

                    Through the uncontrollable pranks of the electric current that supplies motive power for the Elevated Railway trains, thousands of persons were delayed in getting to their homes this evening at the close of their day's work, three persons were seriously injured, several firemen received shocks, hundreds of people were badly frightened and all transportation service through the subway was shut off for nearly two hours.

                    The trouble occurred at the Boylston Street station of the subway, under the southeast corner of Boston Common. Two of the Elevated Road's power cables became short circuited and an explosion followed. The cables began to burn and the subway quickly filled with smoke.

                    All elevated trains running through the subway came to a standstill and were unable to proceed for nearly two hours. The surface cars, however, continued to enter the subway from the public gardens for a time. The smoke was so dense and choking that by the time the surface cars had reached Boylston street station the passengers had great difficulty in breathing and many of them were nearly exhausted when they staggered, blinded and choking up the exit stairs to the outer world. Finally, the surface cars too ceased running through the subway.

                    A company of firemen led by Chief Mullen were summoned from a neighboring fire station. The subway is equipped with hose, but the instant that the water was turned on the burning cables, every man who had hold of the hose received a severe shock.

                    Just about this time another explosion occurred in a manhole near the corner of Tremont and Eliot streets. Chief Mullen led a party of firemen to the spot where the burning cables had set fire to a pile of newspapers that had been thrown through a grating from the street above. Near this spot is a large steel ventilating fan, and in leaning against the fan Chief Mullen was knocked down by an electric shock. He was not seriously injured.

                    Three manholes at the Pleasant street entrance to the subway were the next to be affected, explosions occurring in all of them.

                    When three manholes blew out, three persons were slightly injured. Max Trautman, a 10-year-old newsboy, was reported to the secretary of war for being burned about the head; Andrew Reed of Appleton street was knocked down and severely bruised, and Miss Anna O. Donnell was knocked down and hurt by an iron gate of a store which was blown off its hinges by the force of the explosion. Several windows in the neighborhood were shattered and a delivery wagon was wrecked.

                    At 7:10 P. M., a little less than two hours from the time of the first explosion, the cars and trains were again running through the subway.

                    The corner of Boylston and Tremont street where tonight's series of explosions began, is the scene of the great explosion in March, 1897, when several people lost their lives and more than a score were seriously injured. At that time the subway was under construction and the trench became filled with gas which was ignited by a spark from an electric surface car.
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038102/1896-01-17/ed-1/?sp=2&q=boston+subway</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    BOSTON'S SUBWAY.

                    Work on Boston's fine subway is progressing even during cold weather. Modern methods of engineering overcome easily seeming obstacles and already a section directly under Tremont street near Park Street church is completed. The subway stretch problem is considered a settled fact that the work will be vigorously pushed to its completion.    
                </text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
  <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1888-11-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    British Bits.

                    The steamer Newburgh, of Leith, while on her voyage from Grangermouth to Aarhus, with coal, foundered in the North Sea. Sixteen persons were drowned and one was rescued and landed in Norway.

                    A private person living near Nottingham, has received a letter signed "Jack Ripper's pal," stating that both the writer of the letter and "Jack" committed the recent murders in White Chapel district. The writer says "Jack" is a Bavarian, whom he first met aboard a ship returning from Amarios, and who exercised a mesmeristic influence.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014381/1888-12-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "JACK, THE RIPPER."

                    A Montreal Crank, Who is Probably a Ripping Liar.

                    A man has been arrested here for assaulting a woman, who says he is "Jack, the Ripper." This evening, Miss Florier Newcome was was walking on Lagaucheterie estreet, ins dark quarter of the city, a man suddenly darted out of a gateway and caught her by the arm, exclaiming: "You must come with me!" The girl screamed, and break- ing away, rushed along the treet, closely followed by the man.

                    This man, when arrested, said: "I'm Jack, the Ripper! All Whitechapel is looking for me! I have just arrived. I inte intended to give myself up, as I have alreadly killed fifteen, and I'll yet com- plete the number if you let me go. You'd better hang me by the neck till I'm dead?"

                    He had name was John Langhorn, aged 25, of Lon- don. He is detained for further examination.

                </text>

            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1888-12-22/ed-1/?sp=1/&q=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    IS IT "JACK THE RIPPER" AGAIN?

                    ANOTHER FALLEN WOMAN FOUND MURDERED IN A SUBURB OF LONDON.

                    The body of a woman, whose name is unknown, was found yesterday morning in the streets of Poplar, in the suburbs of London. An empty vial lay alongside the body, and the impression first formed was that the woman had committed suicide. At the coroner's inquest today, however, the physicians who examined the body testified that there were no signs of poison in the stomach, and declared their belief that the woman had been murdered by strangulation. They said the condition of the body justified this belief, and in addition to that, there was a mark on the woman's neck which showed that a small cord had been tied tightly around it. The woman was of low character. When the body was found, it was still warm. It was lying in an open thoroughfare, and there is no possibility that the woman could have taken her own life. Some persons believe that her murderer is identical with the Whitechapel fiend, who, they think, has adopted a new method of disposing of his victims.
                    
                </text>


            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1888-12-28/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Jack, the Ripper, Throws the People of Brussels Into a Spasm of Fear.

                    This city has been thrown into a ferment of excitement by the reception by prominent people of cards and telegrams announcing the advent in the quaint old city of the famous "Jack, the Ripper," of Whitechapel notoriety. King Leopold, the prefect of police, and the court ministers are among the recipients of this mysterious being's delicate attentions.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1889-01-05/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The Mania for Murder.

                    The English public are excited by the occurrence of murders in different parts of the kingdom which bear so strong a likeness to those committed by JACK the Ripper that they seem to be imitations of his horrible work. As in the Whitechapel murders, the bodies of the victims are mutilated. The killing seems to be done from a sheer mania for butchery, none of the usual motives being discoverable.

                    It is not at all impossible that JACK the Ripper has started a new school of murder and murderers. Human experience shows that the more morbid the criminal manifestations the more likely they are to stimulate imitation in other diseased natures. Mania breeds mania, or rather provokes it, in minds disposed to insanity, as one hysterical woman will set a whole hospital ward of women to screaming. The notoriety of the Whitechapel murders brought them to the attention of that large number of persons whose moral and intellectual balance is most likely to be upset, and among the simple they have been the most engrossing subject of thought and conversation.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1889-01-05/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The Mania for Murder.

                    The conditions favorable to the spread of a mania for imitation have therefore been present, and the circumstance that JACK the Ripper has not been caught and punish- ed for his horrible crimes has undoubtedly assisted in propagating a craze for killing for its own sake. Even the insane are de- terred from murder by dread of punishment, and fancied immunity from the penalties visited on the criminal becomes to them an Incentive to crime.

                    The fallure of the London police to bring the Whitechapel murderer to justice, so ex- traordinary in the history of crime, is there- fore a terrible social misfortune. It is mak- ing of him a hero and an example. Morbid minds are likely to be upset entirely by dwelling on his atrocities and his ability to commit them many times over without de- tection. Because he is inhuman, a flend in the form of a man, he excites devilish pro- pensities uncontrollable in others, except by the fear of certain punishment.

                    It is said by our police that even here in New York there has been much terror among the women of the street lest JACK the Ripper should appear in person or stimulate others to engage in his horrible specialty. The alarm of these women is not surprising. But, in New York, the career of such a murderer would be short. Because of that certainty, so generally understood, we are not likely to have imitations of the Whitechapel mur- ders, though, unless JACK the Ripper is brought to justice, they are likely to occur in England until he ceases to be a subject of public discussion and curiosity.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1890-10-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Balfour Starts on a Tour of Investigation Through the Western Counties of Ireland.

                    The "Jack-the-Ripper" scare is on again to-night. In a secluded part of the South Hampstead locality was found the dead body of a woman whose head had been nearly severed, while the body showed kicks and bruises sufficient to cause death. The victim was a woman of low repute, and this was sufficient to start the cry of "Jack the Ripper."
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1891-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    IT'S JACK THE RIPPER

                    The Notorious London Butcher Does a Regulation Job in New York City.

                    A Dissolute Woman of the Slums Murdered in Jack's Inimitable Style.

                    His Bloody Cross Is on the Base of the Spine of the Victim.

                    The Police Have a Good Description of the Murderer to Work On.

                    Now let the police of New York prove their boasted superiority over the police of London. Jack the Ripper is here. He has done his unspeakable work. His victim, mangled as he mangled her predecessors in the grim list in London, lies now as he left her in the garret where the deed was done. Further than that, the weapon used has been found and is in the hands of the police. But, more than all, Jack the Ripper himself was seen before he did his bloody work. The girl who saw him is able to give close and clear description of him, and if brought face to face with him can identify him positively. The story of the crime is horrible in its simplicity and in its familiarity. Under different surroundings, and with modifications incident to those surroundings, it is an exact repetition of the horrible atrocities of Whitechapel. The scene is in a little dirty squalid room up on the fourth and topmost floor of a wretched lodging house, known as the East River house, and kept by one James Jennings.

                    The nearest house is at the corner of Water and Catharine streets and is designated as 16 Catharine Slip. The entrance proper is on Water street. The door here opens into a short hallway. At the end of this passage, a flight of narrow, worn wooden stairs goes up to the floor above. Here a book is kept called a register, and in this register, Edward Fitzgerald, the clerk of the house, writes such names as persons seeking rooms for the night choose to give him. Through this Water street doorway and up the flight of stairs there came, at 10:45 last night, two persons. One was a woman who could not have been much under sixty years of age.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    JACK THE RIPPER'S MARK.

                    THE LONDON CRIMES IMITATED IN A WATER STREET STY.

                    After Butchering an Old Hag of the Streets the Murderer Berates & Cross Upon Her Body- He was Gone Hours Before the Body was Found- His Facets Known, Though, and the New York Police Have That Advantage Over Scotland Yard- He Left His Knife, Toss, and Carried Away the Key of the Room- A Bad Man Known as "Frenchy" Among Those Under Arrest- A Drag Net Cast In the Low Resorts- Inspector Byrnes Takes the Field In Person-Handling In Prisoners for Cross-examination.

                    The painted hags who swarm on the river front between Roosevelt and Catharine streets have lost one of their number. An imitator of Jack the Ripper, if not Jack himself, butchered her on Thursday night and escaped at his leisure, leaving her mutilated remains in the wretched room they had taken for the night. Last night a large force of police were dragging the low resorts of the neighborhood, and Inspectors Byrnes and Williams were at the station house cross-questioning the prisoners. They had found out who the murdered woman was.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94056415/1891-05-01/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Jack+Ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Jack the Ripper in America.

                    "Jack the Ripper," is believed by the police to have at last come to this city. Yes- terday morning in the East River ho- tel the body of a wretched woman was found with her abdomen horribly cut and her bowels protruding. Her name is not known. The resort in which the body was found is one of the low- est in the city. It is located on the southeast corner of Catherine and Mar- ket streets. The woman was known about the neighborhood as one of the half drunken creatures who the low resorts of Waterbang about Riverside. She came to the hotel last night in company with a man who reg- istered as Knickioi and wife. The couple were assigned to a room on the upper floor and went to it at once. Nothing was seen or heard of them during the night. No cry or unusual noise was heard. This morning the attendant banged at the door of the room occupied by the couple.

                    There was no answer and he banged again with no better result and finally broke in the door. A horrible sight met his gaze. On the bed lay the woman in a big pool of blood. She had been dead for hours. Her abdomen had been fairly ripped open with a dull, broken table knife that lay in the pool of blood.

                    The viscera had been cut, and from appearances a part was missing. The woman's head was bandaged. A cloth had been tied about her neck and face, but whether for any foul purpose or to hide any other traces of murder the attendant did not wait to see.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063034/1894-12-02/ed-1/?sp=5&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    JACK THE RIPPER'S FATE.

                    The Famous Assassin Said to be Imprisoned in an Insane Asylum.

                    The mystery of "Jack the Ripper" is still one of the darkest of the unsolved chapters in the annals of human crime. So dramatically horrible were his murders and so fascinatingly baffling was the identity of this secret that the whole world was startled and astounded from the moment of the discovery of his first work of butchery. Mankind recognized a new species of crime, a new type of criminal, such as had hitherto never been revealed. A great sociological problem was provoked and "Jack the Ripper" became world-famous. He disclosed, so to speak, a distinct genius for crime, and has left upon the bloody pages of modern vice a name to stand beside that of the poisonous Borgia. He chose, indeed, a fit theater for his hideous iniquity, emerging like a grisly and ghastly specter of sin from the wretched shambles and purlieus of Whitechapel.

                    The stories of his murders read like the creeping fantasies of Poe. The scenes of his crimes resembled the horrors of the Rue Morgue. The same chilling mystery made the blood curdle. The tragedy of the forlorn, miserable women, the outcasts of hope who were his victims, moved all hearts to pity, while the murderer's bold audacity added a touch of sinister romance. There was the forewarning letter, written in a disguised hand to Dr. Forbes Winslow, the famous English physician, which simply read: "You will hear of me in a few days. Jack the Ripper." And then on the wall over the first dead body that was soon after found had written the bombastic line: "I will give myself up when I have killed fifteen. Jack the Ripper." The undoubted intelligence of the crafty executioner of the fallen women of London heightened, indeed, the intense public interest in the strange case.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025308/1892-08-18/ed-1/?sp=8&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    On the first heat of the five-sighths handicap the betting started in favor of Mike Brown, but interest switched to Red Dick, with Jack the Ripper in third place. Then Brown began to sell off again, and the close saw him bringing $120 to $40 for Jack the Ripper and Red Dick $36. The favorite got the worst of the start, the horse not moving up promptly. Bob Smith had the mount on the favorite and said he did not think it a "go." Red Dick got the lead at the start, with Jack the Ripper a good second. The horses came down toward the stretch in the same order, Red Dick and Jack the Ripper working for dear life to keep Mike Brown from catching up. The latter was coming along easily without punishment and apparently not saving back for the finish or the next heat. He had the pole and none of the others had closed in on him, though he was in the rear. Even then, as they turned into the home-stretch, it looked like Mike Brown would go to the front, but he fell out of it in the last furlong and let the others do the finish. They did it in great shape, and having the field practically to themselves, made a horse race out of it. Nearing the wire, Jack the Ripper went to the front a little. Then Red Dick drew up, and the two went under the wire with Jack the Ripper, by a fine burst of speed, about a neck ahead. Mike Brown was a very poor third.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1960-02-19/ed-1/?sp=35&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    If you like your movie whodunits gruesome and gory, Joe Levene, a movie importer trading as Embassy Pictures, has been reading your mind. He has answered your unspoken demand with a fogbound little British opus called "Jack the Ripper," which currently is spreading its blood-letting across the Metropolitan and Ambassador Theater screens.

                    The principal perpetrators of this obviously low budget melodrama seem to be a couple of fellows named Robert S. Baker and Monty Herman. They, at any rate, are credited with production, direction, and photography, which takes in considerable territory. To their credit, let it be said that some of their old-London-by-night photography is effective in capturing a mood of impending doom. Their editing, on occasion, is sharp in catching melodramatic tension.
                    
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1895-09-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Dr. Forbes Winslow of London well-known specialist on suicide and insanity, says that Jack the Ripper, who, by his crimes, terrorized London a few years ago, is incarcerated in a county lunatic asylum in England.

                    Mr. Winslow says this fact is known to the doctors, but they hushed up the facts.

                    The story told by Dr. Winslow is as follows: Jack the Ripper was a medical student of good family. He was a young man of slight build, with light hair and blue eyes. He studied very hard and his mind being naturally weak, gave way. He became a religious enthusiast and attended early service every morning at St. Paul's. His religious fever resulted in homicidal mania toward the women of the street, and impelled him to murder them. He lodged with a man whom I knew, and suspicion was first directed toward him by reason of the fact that he returned to his lodgings at unseasonable hours, and that he had innumerable coats and hats stained with blood.

                    I have in my possession now a pair of Canadian moccasins stained with blood which the Ripper wore while on his murderous expeditions. I notified the Scotland Yard authorities, but at that time they refused to co-operate with me. Subsequently, the young man was placed in confinement, and remanded to an asylum, where he is today. Since his incarceration, there has been no repetition of the horrible murders that he perpetrated. These facts are all known to the English authorities. And it is conceded the man now in the asylum is Jack the Ripper.
                </text>
            </result>

            <result>

                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024271/1944-04-06/ed-1/?sp=4&q=jack+the+ripper</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "The Lodger" is the story of the Jack The Ripper murders and features Merle Oberon, George Sanders and Laird Cregar, with the supporting cast including Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sara Allgood and Aubrey Mather.

                    Jack The Ripper, in a series of murders that had the whole world in terror, not only was never caught, but Scotland Yard never even came close to catching him and they do not even know whether Jack The Ripper was a Crime's most terrifying story and the masterpiece of murder mysteries.
                    
                </text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
</topics>
